questionsJSON = [{"num":"1","question":"A computer is making a lot of noise. Of the following                    choices, what is the likely problem ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Faulty motherboard","option2":"USB flash drive","option3":"Power supply set to wrong voltage","option4":"Case fan","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A. Incorrect: </b> When motherboards fail, they are                       not noisy. <br/>                      <b>B. Incorrect:</b> Hard disk drives sometimes make a                       lot of noise when they are failing, but not USB flash                       drives. <br/>                      <b>C. Incorrect: </b> If the power supply is set to the                       wrong voltage, it might make a single loud pop when it                       fails, or not work at all, but it won’t make a lot of                       noise.                       <b>D. Correct: </b> So, correct answer is D, When case                       fans begin	to fail, they are often	noisy. They can also                       be noisy if they are dirty","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"2","question":"Another technician ordered a fan for a computer case.	It                   has arrived, and you need to install it. The	original                   fan has been removed. Where should you connect the fan                    power connection ?<br/><br/>","option1":"AC outlet","option2":"P1 power supply connector","option3":"Front panel power","option4":"Motherboard","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A. Incorrect</b> Case fans do not get power from AC                       outlets. <br/>                      <b>B. Incorrect:</b> The P1 connector provides power to                       the motherboard, not to fans. <br/>                      <b>C. Incorrect:</b> Front panels do not have power for                       fans. <br/>                      <b>D. Correct: </b> Fans get power from a connector on                       the motherboard","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"3","question":"A power supply failed after a technician added some hard                   drives to a desktop computer. You need to purchase an                    additional power supply. What is a likely power rating                   you’ll purchase to ensure that the power supply doesn’t                   fail again ? <br/><br/>","option1":"600 W","option2":"600v","option3":"300 W","option4":"250 V","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A. Correct </b> A 600-W power supply is common in                       desktop computers and is the best choice of those given.                       <b>B. Incorrect </b> Power supplies are rated in watts,                       not volts.                       <b>C. Incorrect </b> A 300-W power supply is on the low                       range found with desktop computers. If the original                       failed after adding an additional load with disk drives,                       a larger power supply is needed.                       <b>D. Incorrect </b> Power supplies are rated in watts,                       not volts. ","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"4","question":"Which of the following voltages are not provided by                    ATX-based power supplies ?<br/><br/>","option1":"12 VDC","option2":"-12VDC","option3":"115VAC","option4":"15VDC","answer":"CD","explanation":"<b>A. Incorrect: </b> ATX-based power supplies provide                       12	VDC. <br/>                      <b>B. Incorrect: </b> ATX-based power supplies provide                       -12 VDC. They also	provide	5 VDC and 3.3 VDC. <br/>                      <b>C.  Correct: </b> ATX-based power supplies use AC                       voltage as an input but do not provide AC	voltage. <br/>                      <b>D.  Correct: </b> ATX-based power supplies do not                       provide 15 VDC.","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"5","question":"Molex connectors provide power to disk drives from                    ATX-rated power supplies. What voltages are supplied                    through the Molex connector ?<br/><br/>","option1":"3.3 V and 5 V","option2":"5 V and 12 V","option3":"5 V and 15 V","option4":"12 V and 15 V","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A. Incorrect:</b> 3.3 V is provided to the motherboard                      through the 20-pin or 24-pin P1 connector, but not on                       the Molex connector<br/>                      <b>B.  Correct:</b> Molex connectors supply 5 V and 12 V                       from the power supply to different drives in a computer <br/>                      <b>C.  Incorrect: </b> 5 V is provided through both Molex                       and the P1	motherboard connector, but 15 V is not used in                       ATX power supplies <br/>                      <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> 12 V is provided through both Molex                       and the P1 motherboard connector, but 15 V is not used in                       ATX power supplies","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"6","question":"A system is no longer	booting	to the SATA hard drive,	and                   you suspect that the ATX-based power supply might not	be                   providing the	correct	voltages. What voltages should you                   see on the SATA power connector ? <br/><br/>","option1":"3.3 VDC, 5 VDC, and 12 VDC","option2":"3.3 VDC, 12 VDC, and 15 VDC","option3":"5 VDC, 12 VDC, and 15 VDC","option4":"12 VDC, 15 VDC, and 24 VDC","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct:</b> The correct voltages on a SATA                       connector are 3.3 VDC, 5 VDC, and 12 VDC <br/>                      <b>B.  Incorrect: </b> ATX	power supplies do not provide                       15 VDC <br/>                      <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>ATX power supplies do not provide                       15	VDC <br/>                      <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>ATX power supplies do not provide                       15 VDC or 24 VDC","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"7","question":"Which	of the following can you use to protect against power                   sags ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Commercial power","option2":"Power supply","option3":"UPS","option4":"MSDS","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A. Incorrect: </b>A power sag occurs when the                       commercial	power is lower than normal, so commercial                       power doesn’t protect against it <br/>                      <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Power supplies convert AC to DC,                       but they cannot protect against power sags <br/>                      <b>C.  Correct: </b>An uninterruptible power supply                       (UPS) uses	a battery backup to protect against power                       sags. Flickering lights are an indication of power sags <br/>                       <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Material Safety Data	Sheets                       (MSDSs) provide safety-related information for items used                       within a work environment","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"8","question":"Which of the following can protect against ESD damage                    ? <br/><br/>","option1":"ESD wrist strap","option2":"Reducing humidity as much as possible","option3":"Ensuring that computers are stored on carpets whenever                   possible","option4":"ESD mat","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Electrostatic discharge (ESD) wrist                       straps protect against ESD	damage </br>                      <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Low humidity generates more static.                       Ideally, humidity should be around 50 percent <br/>                      <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Carpets generate static easily, so                       it’s best not to store computers on carpets <br/>                      <b>D.  Correct: </b>ESD mats also protect against ESD","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"9","question":"You want to verify that a power supply is providing proper                    voltage while it's connected to the P1 connector on the                    motherboard. What would you use ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Surge suppressor","option2":"Multimeter","option3":"Power strip","option4":"Power supply tester","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	surge	suppressor	will	prevent	power	spikes	from	reaching	a	computer, but	it	doesn’t	measure	voltages <br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>A	multimeter	can	measure	DC	voltages	provided	to	a	motherboard	on	the P1	connector <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>A	power	strip	provides	unprotected	power	to	a	system	but	doesn’t measure	voltage <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	power	supply	tester	can	test	an	unconnected	power	supply,	but	it	isn’t used	for	a	power	supply	plugged	into	a	system","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"10","question":"You open a computer to troubleshoot it and notice an                    excessive amount of dust inside it. Of the following                    choices, what is the best choice to clean it ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Lint-free cloth","option2":"Vaccum cleaner","option3":"Glass cleaner","option4":"Compressed air","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Lint-free	cloths	are	used	to	clean	screens	but	would	not	be	used	for	an excessive	amount	of	dust<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>An	antistatic	vacuum	cleaner	could	be	used	but	a	standard	vacuum cleaner	can	cause	ESD	damage <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Glass	cleaner	includes	ammonia	and	alcohol,	which	might	damage	internal	components<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Compressed	air	would	be	the	best	choice	for	blowing	out	the	dust","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"11","question":"Which of the following can contribute to ESD damage                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Case fans","option2":"Carpet","option3":"Touching the computer case while working on a computer","option4":"ESD mats","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Case	fans	keep	a	system	cool	but	do	not	contribute	to	ESD	damage<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>Static	builds	up	on	carpet,	so	placing	computers	on	carpets	can	contribute to	ESD	damage <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Touching	the	computer	case	while	working	on	a	computer	helps	keep you	at	the	same	potential	as	the	computer	and	reduces	static	buildup<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>ESD	mats	reduce	the	potential	for	ESD	damage","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"12","question":"After cleaning a computer screen with	a cleaning compound,                    your fingers start to	develop	a rash. What can you use to                    quickly identify what was in the cleaning compound ? <br/><br/>","option1":"MSDS","option2":"Internet","option3":"Local hospital","option4":"Coworkers","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>A	Material	Safety	Data	Sheet	(MSDS)	documents	characteristics	of	materials	used	within	a	workplace<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>You	might	be	able	to	find	the	information	on	the	Internet,	but	an	MSDS sheet	should	be	readily	available<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Medical	personnel	will	likely	want	to	know	what	was	in	the	cleaning compound,	but	they	wouldn’t	know	what	was	used <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Coworkers	wouldn’t	be	the	best	source	to	identify	the	contents,	but	they can	retrieve	the	MSDS","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"13","question":"Which of the following choices lists common motherboard                    form factors from the smallest to the largest ?<br/>","option1":"Pico-ITX, mini-ITX, micro-ATX, ATX","option2":"Pico-ITX, micro-ATX, mini-ITX, ATX","option3":"ATX, Pico-ITX, mini-ITX, micro-ATX","option4":"Mini-ITX, micro-ATX, Pico-ITX, ATX","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Pico-ITX	form	factors	are	3.9	x	2.8	inches,	Mini-ITX	are	6.7	x	6.7	inches, micro-ATX	are	between	6.75	x	6.75	inches	and	9.6	x	9.6	inches,	and	ATX	form	factors	are	12	x	9.6	inches <br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Micro-ATX	is	smaller	than	mini-ITX <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>ATX	is	the	largest,	not	the	smallest<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Pico-ITX	is	the	smallest","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"14","question":"Of the following choices, what two components determine the                    speed of a bus ?<br/>","option1":"Bit size and multiplier","option2":"Crystal frequency and bit size","option3":"Crystal frequency and multiplier","option4":"CPU capability and cache size","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b>The	bit	size	(such	as	32-bit	or	64-bit)	determines	the	data	throughput, not	the	speed<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>The	bit	size	determines	the	data	throughput<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>The	frequency	of	the	oscillator	crystal	and	the	multiplier	combine	to determine	a	bus	speed<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>The	CPU	uses	the	clock	speed,	but	it	doesn’t	determine	the	speed","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"15","question":"You have PCIe x2 card that you want to install into a                    computer. Of the following choices, where could you                    install it ?<br/>","option1":"PCIe x1 expansion slot","option2":"PCIe X4 expansion slot","option3":"PCI expansion slot","option4":"PCI-X expansion slot","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	larger	PCIe	card	will	not	fit	in	a	smaller	PCIe	slot<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>You	can	plug	smaller	PCIe	cards	into	larger	PCIe	slots,	so	a	PCIe	x2	card will	fit	in	a	PCIe	x4	slot<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>PCIe	cards	are	not	compatible	with	PCI	slots<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>PCIe	cards	are	not	compatible	with	PCI-X	slots","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"16","question":"You are trying to start a system from a bootable DVD, but                    the system always boots to the hard drive instead.                    What should you do ?<br/>","option1":"Replace the DVD","option2":"Replace the DVD drive","option3":"Manipulate the start sequence in the BIOS","option4":"Flash the BIOS","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> Replacing	the	DVD	might	be	necessary,	but	you	should	check	the	BIOS first<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Replacing	the	DVD	drive	might	be	necessary,	but	you	should	check	the BIOS	first <br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>You	can	change	the	boot	order	in	the	BIOS	so	that	the	system	tries	to boot	to	the	DVD	first <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>You	would	flash	the	BIOS	only	if	it	needed	to	be	upgraded.	You	should try	to	change	the	settings	first","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"17","question":"When starting a computer, you see a message indicating a                    CMOS error. What is the most likely solution ?<br/>","option1":"Flash the CMOS","option2":"Flash the BIOS","option3":"Replace the battery","option4":"Replcae the CMOS","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>The	CMOS	isn’t	flashed.	Settings	in	the	CMOS	are	configured	by	the	user and	retained	by	battery	power <br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>You’d	flash	the	BIOS	to	upgrade	it,	but	an	upgrade	wouldn’t	solve	this problem <br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>This	error	indicates	that	the	settings	in	CMOS	aren’t	being	retained	by	the current	battery <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> The	BIOS	is	normally	soldered	into	the	motherboard,	and	it’s	rare	to replace	it","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"18","question":"After trying to run virtualization software, you realize                    that the BIOS doesn't support virtualization. What should                    you do ?<br/>","option1":"Upgrade the CPU","option2":"Upgrade the motherboard","option3":"Replace the CMOS battery","option4":"Flash the BIOS","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b>The	current	CPU	might	support	virtualization,	but	it	must	be	enabled	in BIOS <br/> <b>B.  Incorrect:</b>Upgrading	the	motherboard	might	not	be	necessary.	The	BIOS	should be	upgraded	first <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b>The	battery	doesn’t	determine	whether	virtualization	is	supported <br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>If	the	BIOS	doesn’t	support	an	option,	you	can	often	upgrade	it	by	flashing	the	BIOS	to	get	the	new	feature","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"19","question":"You are replacing two DDR3 DIMMs in a Intel dual-channel motherboard. Into which slots should you put them ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Two different-colored slots","option2":"Two identical-colored slots","option3":"Separate banks","option4":"Slots 1 and 4","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Different-colored	slots	indicate	different	banks <br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>Dual-channel	RAM	should	be	installed	in	the	same	bank,	which	is	the same	color	on	most	motherboards<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> If	you	place	the	RAM	in	different	banks,	it	will	be	used	as	single-channel RAM	instead	of	dual-channel	RAM <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> Slots	1	and	4	are	always	in	different	banks","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"20","question":"You are shopping for replacement DDR3 RAM. Your system has                    a 400-MHz clock. What should you buy ?<br/><br/>","option1":"PC3-400","option2":"DDR3-400","option3":"PC3-25600","option4":"PC3-12800","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>PC3-400	indicates	a	clock	speed	of	50	MHz<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>If	the	DDR3	name	is	used,	it	is	identified	as	the	clock	times	8.	400	×	8	= 3,200,	or	DDR3-3200 <br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>The	calculation	for	DDR3	is	Clk	×	4	×	2	×	64	/	8.	400	MHz	×	4	×	2	×	64	/ 8	=	25,600,	so	it	is	PC3-25600 <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> PC3-12800	indicates	a	clock	speed	of	200	MHz","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"21","question":"An Intel CPU has two cores, but the operating system shoes                    it has four CPUs. What feature allows this to happen ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Hyper-threading","option2":"HyperTransport","option3":"Dual-channel RAM","option4":"L2 cache","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Hyper-threading	is	supported	on	Intel	CPUs	and	allows	each	core	to appear	as	two	CPUs <br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>HyperTransport	is	used	on	AMD	processors	in	place	of	a	front	side	bus <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Dual	channel	RAM	provides	two	paths	to	RAM,	but	it	does	not	affect the	CPU	cores<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>L2	cache	is	fast	RAM	stored	on	the	CPU	for	improved	performance,	but it	does	not	affect	the	CPU	cores","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"22","question":"Of the following choices, which is fastest ?<br/><br/>","option1":"L1 cache","option2":"L2 cache","option3":"L3 cache","option4":"Triple-channel DDR3","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>L1	cache	is	a	fast	cache,	close	to	the	CPU<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>L2	cache	is	slower	than	L1	cache<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>L3	cache	is	slower	than	L1	and	L2	cache<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Any	type	of	DDR	RAM	is	slower	than	L1,	L2,	or	L3	cache","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"23","question":"Which of the following replces the Intel Socket H ?<br/><br/>","option1":"LGA 775","option2":"LGA 1366","option3":"LGA 1156","option4":"LGA 1155","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>LGA	775	is	Socket	T	and	was	replaced	by	Socket	B<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>LGA	1366	is	Socket	B<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>LGA	1156	is	Socket	H<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>The	LGA	1155	is	also	known	as	Socket	H2	and	replaces	Socket	H	or	H1","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"24","question":"You are asked to troubleshoot a computer that is randomly                    rebooting or failing. Of the following choices, what                    hardware can cause these symtoms ?<br/><br/>","option1":"RAM","option2":"Fan","option3":"Power supply","option4":"Virus","answer":"ABC","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Faulty	RAM	can	cause	these	symptoms<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>Failing	or	dirty	fans	can	result	in	overheating	problems,	causing	these symptoms<br/> <b>C.  Correct:</b> A	power	supply	providing	varying	voltages	or	voltages	out	of	specifications	can	cause	these	symptoms<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b> Viruses	can	cause	these	types	of	symptoms,	but	a	virus	is	software,	not hardware","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"25","question":"You are adding an internal SATA drive to an existing system.                    How many drives can you connect to a SATA connector ?<br/><br/>","option1":"One","option2":"Two","option3":"Three","option4":"Four","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>SATA	connectors	support	only	one	drive<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect:</b> IDE	connectors	support	two	drives<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>None	of	the	interfaces	support	three	drives <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	single	motherboard	includes	two	IDE	drives	and	can	support	four SATA	drives","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"26","question":"What type of data connector is used for a SATA 3G drive ?<br/><br/>","option1":"40-pin, 40-wire ribbon cable","option2":"40-pin, 80-wire ribbon cable","option3":"7 pins with an L-shaped connector","option4":"15 pins with an L-shaped connector","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Older	PATA	drives	use	40-pin,	40-wire	cables<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Newer	PATA	drives	use	40-pin,	80-wire	cables<br/> <b>C.  Correct:</b> SATA	data	connectors	use	a	7-pin	L-shaped	connector<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> SATA	power	uses	a	15-pin	L-shaped	connector","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"27","question":"Which of the following is not a valid external connector                    for a hard drive ?<br/><br/>","option1":"USB","option2":"FireWire","option3":"eSATA","option4":"1934b","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>USB	connectors	can	be	used	to	connect	drives<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>FireWire	connectors	can	be	used	to	connect	drives<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Hard	disk	drives	can	be	connected	with	eSATA<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>1394a	and	1394B	are	FireWire	400	and	FireWire	800,	but	an	external	connector	named	1934b	doesn’t	exist","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"28","question":"How much data can you store on a DL DVD disc ?<br/><br>","option1":"700 MB","option2":"4.7 GB","option3":"8.5 GB","option4":"17.1 GB","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	standard	CD	holds	700	MB<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	single-layer	DVD	holds	4.7	GB<br/> <b>C.  Correct:</b> A	dual-layer	DVD	holds	8.5	GB<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	dual-layer	double-sided	DVD	holds	17.1	GB","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"29","question":"What is the minimum number of drives in a RAID-1 ?<br/><br/>","option1":"One","option2":"Two","option3":"Three","option4":"Four","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>None	of	the	RAID	configurations	use	one	drive<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>RAID-1	(mirror)	uses	only	two	drives<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>RAID-5	requires	a	minimum	of	three	drives<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> RAID-10	requires	a	minimum	of	four	drives","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"30","question":"You hear a hard drive making loud clicking noises.                    What does this indicate ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Failing hard drive","option2":"Normal operation","option3":"Disk thrashing","option4":"Bad clusters","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>This	indicates	a	failing	hard	disk	drive <br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Clicking	noises	from	a	hard	disk	drive	are	not	normal <br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Disk	thrashing	is	when	you	can	hear	the	actuator	busily	working	and	see the	LED	constantly	blinking <br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Bad	clusters	will	give	read	and	write	errors","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"31","question":"How many USB devices can a USB controller support ?<br/>","option1":"2","option2":"4","option3":"63","option4":"127","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> A	controller	supports	more	than	2	devices<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect:</b> A	controller	supports	more	than	4	devices<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> FireWire	supports	as	many	as	63	devices<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>A	USB	controller	supports	as	many	as	127	devices","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"32","question":"You want to plug in a USB 3.0 device. What port should you                    use ?<br/><br/>","option1":"A blue rectangular port","option2":"A rectangular port with a curved top","option3":"A pink TRS connector","option4":"A green PS/2 connector","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct:</b> USB	3.0	ports	are	blue	and	the	same	rectangular	size	as	USB	1.1	and	USB 2.0	ports<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	FireWire	port	is	rectangular	with	a	curved	top<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Microphones	have	tip	ring	sleeve	(TRS)	connectors	and	plug	into	a pink	port<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>The	green	PS/2	connector	is	for	the	mouse","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"33","question":"What is the maximum length of a FireWire 400 cable ?                   <br/><br/>","option1":"3 meters","option2":"5 meters","option3":"4.5 meters","option4":"100 meters","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </B>The	maximum	recommended	length	of	a	USB	3.0	cable	is	3	meters<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>The	maximum	length	of	a	USB	cable	is	5	meters<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>The	maximum	length	of	a	FireWire	400	cable	is	4.5	meters<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>The	maximum	length	of	a	FireWire	800	cable	using	a	Category	5e twisted-pair	cable	is	100	meters","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"34","question":"You want to control two computers with a single keyboard,                    mouse, and monitor. What should you use ?<br/><br/>","option1":"PCIe expansion card","option2":"KVM switch","option3":"MIDI device","option4":"7.1 system","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>An	expansion	expands	the	capabilities	of	a	single	computer<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>A	keyboard	video	mouse	(KVM)	switch	is	used	to	manage	more	than	one computer	with	a	single	keyboard,	mouse,	and	monitor<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> A	Musical	Instrument	Digital	Interface	(MIDI)	device	is	used	to	play	MIDI music	files<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> A	7.1	system	is	a	surround	sound	system	with	seven	speakers	and	a subwoofer","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"35","question":"You need to identify a device that can create files from                    printed documents. Of the following choices,                    What would you select ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Multifunction printer","option2":"Biometric device","option3":"Barcode reader","option4":"MIDI-enabled device","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Multifunction	printers	commonly	include	scanners	or	digitizers	that	can scan	documents<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	biometric	device	reads	information	about	a	person,	such	as	a	fingerprint	or	eye	retina<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>A	barcode	reader	includes	a	scanner,	but	it	can	read	only	barcodes<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> A	MIDI-enabled	device	can	play	synthesized	music	from	MIDI	files","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"36","question":"You want to watch and record TV shows on a desktop computer.                    What is needed ?<br/><br/>","option1":"KVM switch","option2":"Webcam","option3":"TV tuner card","option4":"Camcorder","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	KVM	switch	allows	multiple	computers	to	share	a	single	keyboard, video	monitor,	and	mouse<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	webcam	is	a	camera	attached	to	the	computer	and	is	used	for	live interactions,	such	as	a	phone	call<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>A	TV	tuner	card	is	required	to	watch	and	record	TV	shows	on	a	desktop computer<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	camcorder	provides	video	recordings","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"37","question":"Of the following display interfaces, what uses an analog                    signal ?<br/>","option1":"HDMI","option2":"DVI-D","option3":"DVI-A","option4":"VGA","answer":"CD","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>High-Definition	Multimedia	Interface	(HDMI)	uses	digital	transmissions<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Digital	Visual	Interface—Digital	(DVI-D)	uses	digital	transmissions<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>Digital	Visual	Interface—Analog	(DVI-A)	uses	analog	transmissions<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Video	Graphics	Array	(VGA)	uses	analog	transmissions","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"38","question":"Which of the following display interfaces include both                    audio and video signals ?<br/>","option1":"HDMI","option2":"DVI-D","option3":"DVI-A","option4":"VGA","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>High-Definition	Multimedia	Interface	(HDMI)	includes	both	8-channel audio	and	video<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Digital	Visual	Interface—Digital	(DVI-D)	includes	video	in	only	a	digital format<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Digital	Visual	Interface—Analog	(DVI-A)	includes	video	in	only	an	analog	format<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Video	Graphics	Array	(VGA)	uses	only	analog	video","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"39","question":"You have a computer with a DVI port and an HDMI port. One                    monitor is connected to the DVI port, and you want to add a                    second monitor. The second monitor has a single VGA port.                    How can you accomplish this ? <br/>","option1":"Plug the VGA cable into the HDMI port","option2":"Use a passive VGA-to-HDMI adapter","option3":"Plug the VGA cable into the DVI port, and plug the DVI                   cable into the HDMI port","option4":"None of the above","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	VGA	cable	with	a	DB-15	connector	will	not	plug	into	an	HDMI	port<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	passive	adapter	cannot	convert	analog	VGA	signals	to	digital	HDMI signals<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>The	VGA	cable	cannot	plug	into	a	DVI	port,	and	the	DVI	cable	can’t	plug into	the	HDMI	port<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>HDMI	is	digital,	and	VGA	is	analog,	and	none	of	these	solutions	can	convert	the	signals","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"40","question":"Your company is replacing all the the CRT monitors with                    flat panel displays. What should be done with the old                    monitors ?<br/>","option1":"Take them directly to a landfill","option2":"Throw them in the dimpster","option3":"Take them to an incinerator","option4":"Dispose of them as hazardous waste in compliance with local                   regulations","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Monitors	should	not	be	taken	to	a	landfill<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Monitors	thrown	in	the	dumpster	go	to	a	landfill<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> Monitors	should	not	be	incinerated<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>CRT	monitors	include	toxic	substances	and	should	be	disposed	of	as	hazardous	waste","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"41","question":"You have recently installed a new video card with a DVI                    interface. The display always defaults to VGA mode and                    can't be changed. What is the most likely problem ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Nothing; this is normal for DVI","option2":"Incorrect driver","option3":"Faulty monitor","option4":"Faulty video card","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>VGA	mode	(640	×	480)	is	not	common	for	DVI<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>The	most	common	reason	for	a	new	video	card	defaulting	to	VGA	mode is	an	incorrect	driver<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Problems	with	the	monitor	can	affect	the	display	quality	but	wouldn’t change	the	resolution<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> A	faulty	video	card	can	default	to	VGA	mode,	but	it	is	much	more	likely that	the	driver	isn’t	installed	for	the	new	video	card","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"42","question":"You are troubleshooting a problem with a blank LCD display.                    You have verified that it is connected to the computer and                    has power. What's the most likely problem ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Incorrect driver","option2":"Faulty CRT tube","option3":"Failed backlight","option4":"Dead pixels","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>An	incorrect	driver	would	give	some	other	symptoms<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>An	LCD	monitor	does	not	have	a	CRT	tube<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>LCD	crystals	do	not	emit	light,	so	the	most	likely	problem	is	that	the	backlight	failed<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>LCDs	might	have	a	few	dead	pixels,	but	if	the	screen	is	completely	blank, all	the	pixels	would	be	dead","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"43","question":"What is a duplexing assembly used for in a printer                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"To print on both sides of the paper","option2":"To improve RAID-1","option3":"To allow two-way communication","option4":"To double the speed of the printer","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Duplexing	assemblies	can	automatically	flip	paper	in	a	printer	to	print both	sides<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Duplexing	improves	RAID-1	by	adding	a	second	disk	controller,	but	this is	not	related	to	printers<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>In	networking,	duplex	indicates	a	device	has	two-way	communication, but	that	is	unrelated	to	printers<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>They	do	not	increase	the	speed","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"44","question":"A customer wants to buy a printer for home use that can                    print color. She asks you for your advice. What would you                    recommend ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Dot matrix printer","option2":"Color laser printer","option3":"Inkjet printer","option4":"Laser printer","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	dot	matrix	printer	would	be	appropriate	if	she	wanted	to	print multipart	forms<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>A	color	laser	printer	is	much	more	expensive	than	an	inkjet	printer<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>Inkjet	printers	print	color	and	are	very	popular	for	home	users<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Regular	laser	printers	do	not	print	color","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"45","question":"You are preparing to replace a toner cartridge on a laser                    printer. Which of the following steps should you take                    first ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Restart the print spooler","option2":"Turn off the printer","option3":"Remove the new toner from the package","option4":"Print a test page","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Restart	the	spooler	if	the	queue	is	backed	up<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>You	should	turn	off	the	printer	as	a	safety	precaution	before	servicing	a laser	printer<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>You	should	unpack	the	new	toner	only	when	you’re	ready	to	install	it<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>You	could	print	a	test	page	as	a	final	step	to	confirm	proper	operation of	the	printer","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"46","question":"Of the following choices, what is not used to connect a                    wired printer ?<br/><br/>","option1":"USB","option2":"Parallel","option3":"802.11","option4":"Ethernet","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>USB	is	the	most	common	method<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Parallel	is	not	a	common	method,	but	it	has	been	used	to	connect	a wired	printer<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>802.11	refers	to	wireless	technologies<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Ethernet	is	used	to	connect	printers	over	a	wired	network","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"47","question":"What should you do if an inkjet printer is printing random                    streaks ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Replace the toner cartridge","option2":"Clean the fusing assembly","option3":"Update the drivers","option4":"Clean the print heads","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Inkjet	printers	do	not	have	toner	cartridges<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Inkjet	printers	do	not	have	fusing	assemblies<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> A	driver	would	not	cause	random	streaks<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Cleaning	and	aligning	the	print	heads	will	likely	resolve	this	problem","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"48","question":"You are troubleshooting a problem with a HP6L laser printer.                    One LED is steady red, and another is blinking orange.                    The customer complains that it prints streaks in the same                    place on every page. What is the most likely problem                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"The imaging drum","option2":"The fuser","option3":"An incorrect print driver","option4":"Impossible to tell without the manual","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Streaks	are	very	likely	caused	by	scratches	on	the	imaging	drum	for	any type	of	laser	printer<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>If	toner	wasn’t	sticking	to	the	paper,	the	fuser	is	the	likely	problem<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>The	wrong	driver	results	in	garbled	output<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>The	manual	will	help	you	interpret	the	lights,	but	the	streaks	indicate	a scratched	drum","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"49","question":"Which key can often be used with a function key to disable                    wireless on a laptop computer <br/><br/>","option1":"F1 key","option2":"Num Lock key","option3":"Fn key","option4":"Caps Lock key","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> The	F1	key	by	itself	is	used	to	open	Help<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>The	Num	Lock	key	configures	the	numeric	keypad	to	use	numbers	or	as navigation	keys<br/> <b>C.  Correct:</b> The	Fn	key	is	often	used	with	a	function	key	to	disable	wireless<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> The	Caps	Lock	key	configures	letters	to	be	always	uppercase	or lowercase","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"50","question":"Which of the following best describes a docking station                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"A device designed to enhance the capabilities of a laptop                   and allow it to function as a desktop computer","option2":"A device that has one connection and provides additional                   ports for the laptop","option3":"A component that provides AC power to an LED display","option4":"A component used for laptop physical security","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct:</b> Docking	stations	provide	additional	capabilities	to	laptops	when	used	in an	office<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Port	replicators	provide	additional	ports<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>An	inverter	provides	AC	power	to	LED	displays<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Cable	locks	are	used	for	physical	security","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"51","question":"A laptop display is dark, but you can see information on                    the screen when you shine a flashlight into it. Of the the                    following choices, what is the problem ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Backlight","option2":"Inverter","option3":"LCD display","option4":"Video card","answer":"AB","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct:</b> If	the	backlight	fails,	the	display	will	be	dark	or	dim<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>The	inverter	powers	the	backlight	on	LCD	laptop	displays,	so	it	can	exhibit these	symptoms<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> Data	can	be	viewed	when	the	flashlight	is	shined	into	the	panel,	so	the LCD	display	has	not	failed<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>If	the	video	card	failed,	you	wouldn’t	see	any	display","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"52","question":"You are preparing to replace the keyboard in a laptop                    computer. Of the following choices, what should you                    include in the process?<br/><br/>","option1":"Toggle the Fn key before starting","option2":"Obtain the manufacturer's documentation for the laptop","option3":"Remove the LCD display first","option4":"Remove all power including the battery","answer":"BD","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>It	is	not	necessary	to	toggle	any	keys	before	starting<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>The	documentation	provides	the	steps	you’ll	use<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> The	display	usually	isn’t	replaced	before	the	keyboard,	but	the	manual provides	the	specific	steps<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>All	power	should	be	removed	before	starting","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"53","question":"A user wants to conserve power on his system when he's not                    using it. Which of the following saves the most power ?                   <br/><br/>","option1":"Turning off the display after inactivity","option2":"Turning off disks after inactivity","option3":"Sleep","option4":"Hibernate","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Turning	off	just	the	display	is	useful,	but	other	components	are	still consuming	power<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Turning	off	just	the	disks	is	useful,	but	other	components	are	still	consuming	power<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Sleep	mode	reduces	power	consumption	but	not	as	much	as	hibernate<br/> <b>D.  Correct:</b> A	system	turns	off	in	Hibernate	mode,	so	this	saves	the	most	power","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"54","question":"Wireless has failed on a laptop computer. Which of the                    following options would restore the capability ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Install a Mini-PCIe card","option2":"Install a USB wireless adapter","option3":"Install a PCI wireless card","option4":"Install a AGP wireless adapter","answer":"AB","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>A	Mini-PCIe	card	can	add	wireless	to	a	laptop<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>A	USB	wireless	adapter	can	add	wireless	to	a	laptop<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>PCI	cards	won’t	fit	in	a	laptop<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>AGP	is	a	video	technology	bus","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"55","question":"Of the following choices, what would cause a device to                    change from portrait mode to landscape mode when the                    device is moved ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Touch flow","option2":"Accelerometer","option3":"Gyro","option4":"Geotracking","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Touch	flow	is	used	to	sense	when	a	user	moves	a	finger	across	a	touch screen<br/> <b>B.  Correct:</b> Devices	commonly	include	accelerometers	(and	electronic	gyroscopes)	to sense	the	orientation	of	the	device	and	change	the	display<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> A	gyro	is	type	of	sandwich	sold	in	many	Greek	restaurants,	wrapped	in	a flatbread	or	pita<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Geotracking	uses	recorded	GPS	information	to	track	the	past	locations of	a	device","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"56","question":"Of the following choices, what represents a benefit to                    users of purchasing apps only through Apple's App Store                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Cheaper than purchasing at a store","option2":"Automatically includes source code","option3":"Upgrades are automatic","option4":"Less chance of downloading malicious software","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>You	can’t	purchase	Apple	Apps	at	a	store,	so	there	is	no	cost	benefit. B.  Incorrect: Purchased	software	is	typically	closed	source,	so	it	does	not	include	the source	code<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>While	software	can	often	be	upgraded,	upgrades	are	not	automatic	with Apple	App	Store	apps<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Apple	screens	all	software	in	their	App	Store,	so	software	purchased through	their	site	is	less	likely	to	be	infected	with	a	virus	or	other	malicious software","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"57","question":"What is required before using two Bluetooth devices                    together ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Subscribe to a cellular plan","option2":"Connect to a Wi-Fi network","option3":"Enable POP3","option4":"Pair them","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> Cellular	plans	are	used	with	smartphones	and	some	mobile	devices,	but they	are	unrelated	to	Bluetooth<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Connecting	to	a	wireless	network	is	not	required	to	pair	two	Bluetooth devices<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Post	Office	Protocol	v3	(POP3)	is	configured	for	email	but	not	for Bluetooth<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Bluetooth	devices	must	be	paired	before	they	can	be	used	together.	This can	be	automatic	or	can	require	entering	a	PIN	on	one	or	both	devices","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"58","question":"You are helping a user configure email on a tablet. It is                    prompting you for the port used for secure POP3. What is                    the most likely port number you should enter ?<br/><br/>","option1":"25","option2":"110","option3":"993","option4":"995","answer":"D","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> Port	25	is	the	well-known	port	for	Simple	Mail	Transport	Protocol (SMTP)<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>Port	110	is	the	well-known	port	for	Post	Office	Protocol3	(POP3)<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>Port	993	is	the	well-known	port	for	IMAP	over	Secure	Sockets	Layer (IMAPS)<br/> <b>D.  Correct: </b>Port	995	is	the	well-known	port	for	POP3	over	Secure	Sockets	Layer (POP3S)","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"59","question":"A business owner wants to ensure that her tablet is as                    secure as possible. Of the following choices, what should                    she enable ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Remote wipe","option2":"GPS location services","option3":"passcode lock","option4":"Bluetooth pairing","answer":"ABC","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>Remote	wipe	allows	her	to	send	a	remote	signal	to	a	lost	device	to	delete all	information	on	the	device<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>Global	Positioning	System	(GPS)	location	services	allow	a	lost	device	to	be located<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>Passcode	locks	require	a	user	to	enter	a	passcode	before	using	a	device<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Bluetooth	pairing	is	done	to	match	two	Bluetooth	devices.	However,	you don’t	enable	Bluetooth	pairing.	Instead,	you	pair	devices	after	enabling	Bluetooth","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"60","question":"What should you do before updating the operating system of                    a mobile device ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Flash the BIOS","option2":"Back up the device","option3":"Enable remote wipe","option4":"Disable Wi-Fi and cellular connections","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>Flashing	the	BIOS	is	commonly	done	for	a	motherboard	BIOS	to	update it.	It	can	be	done	on	a	mobile	device,	but	it	is	not	necessary	before	an	update<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>It’s	possible	to	lose	data,	applications,	and	settings	during	an	update,	so all	data	should	be	backed	up	before	an	update	whenever	possible<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> Remote	wipe	is	a	security	feature	that	allows	you	to	remove	data	on	a lost	device<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>It	is	not	necessary	to	disable	connectivity	during	an	update,	and	sometimes	the	connectivity	is	required","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"61","question":"You are working with a customer to resolve a problem with                    his laptop, and your personal cell phone rings, What should                    you do ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Ignore it","option2":"Switch the cell phone to vibrate","option3":"Excuse yourself and answer the phone","option4":"Explain that it is an emergency and that you have to answer the phone","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	ringing	phone	that	can	be	heard	by	you	and	the	customer	is	disruptive,	so	it	should	not	be	ignored<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>The	best	choice	is	switch	the	phone	to	vibrate	and	return	your	attention to	the	customer<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> Your	attention	should	stay	with	the	customer<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>You	have	no	idea	whether	it’s	an	emergency	or	not,	and	lying	about	it will	easily	be	recognized	by	the	customer","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"62","question":"You are a technician helping an executive reslove a problem                    with her computer. While helping her, you see some                    confidential company papers on her printer. Of the following                    choices, what is acceptable ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Look at the papers only if she leaves","option2":"Throw them away","option3":"Ignore them","option4":"Tell her se shouldn't print them","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> It	is	not	acceptable	to	snoop	through	someone’s	papers	even	if	they leave	the	room<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect: </b>You	should	not	throw	away	someone	else’s	property<br/> <b>C.  Correct: </b>You	should	respect	customers’	confidential	property,	so	the	best	solution of	those	given	is	to	ignore	them<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>There	is	no	indication	that	she	should	not	use	her	printer	for	printing confidential	papers","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"63","question":"A network printer with multiple paper trays was no longer                    printing due to a network problem. A technician reconfigured                    the printer and verified that it was connected. Later,                    customers complained that the printer could print to one                    tray but not the other. What troubleshooting step did the                    technician miss ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Identify the problem","option2":"Verify full system functionality","option3":"Establish a plan of action to resolve the problem","option4":"Documentation","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>The	first	step	is	to	identify	the	problem,	and	the	technician	did	so	for	the original	problem<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>The	fifth	step	in	the	CompTIA	troubleshooting	model	is	to	verify	full system	functionality	after	resolving	a	problem.	In	this	case,	the	technician	likely bumped	or	opened	the	second	tray,	preventing	it	from	printing<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect: </b>The	technician	did	establish	a	plan	of	action	and	did	resolve	the	original problem<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>Documentation	is	the	last	step,	and	it	could	be	that	the	technician	was documenting	that	the	problem	was	resolved	at	the	same	time	that	the	customers identified	the	second	problem","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"64","question":"Sally wants to purchase a computer that she'll use as a                    basic computer at home. She plans on doing research on the                    internet, accessing email, and writing some documents.                     Which of the following choices best meets her needs ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Thick client","option2":"Thin client","option3":"HTPC","option4":"Virtualization workstation","answer":"A","explanation":"<b>A.  Correct: </b>A	standard	thick	client	includes	an	operating	system	and	application needed	by	typical	users<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect:</b> A	thin	client	has	minimal	software	and	connects	to	a	remote	system	for most	applications<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> A	home	theatre	PC	(HTPC)	is	used	for	TV,	movies,	and	music<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	virtualization	workstation	is	used	to	run	one	or	more	multiple	VMs within	the	host	but	isn’t	needed	here","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"65","question":"Of the following types of workstations, which would most likely use a high-end liquid cooling system ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Thick client","option2":"Gaming PC","option3":"Home server","option4":"Home theater PC","answer":"B","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect: </b>A	thick	client	is	a	standard	PC	and	doesn’t	require	any	high-end components<br/> <b>B.  Correct: </b>Gaming	PCs	often	use	high-end	cooling,	such	as	a	liquid-cooling	system to	keep	the	systems	from	overheating<br/> <b>C.  Incorrect:</b> Home	servers	require	high-end	disk	subsystems	and	fast	network	interface	cards	but	would	not	require	high-end	cooling<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect:</b> A	home	theater	PC	requires	high-quality	graphics,	sound,	and	a	TV tuner,	but	not	high-end	cooling","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"66","question":"A user is planning to add a home server PC that will be used                    by five users in his home for data sharing. He asks you what                    type of disk storage would be best. What would you                    recommend ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Solid state disk","option2":"Blu-ray","option3":"RAID array","option4":"HDMI-compatible","answer":"C","explanation":"<b>A.  Incorrect:</b> A	solid	state	disk	(SSD)	is	quick	but	is	often	very	expensive	and	not	the best	choice	for	a	home	server	that	will	be	storing	a	high	volume	of	data<br/> <b>B.  Incorrect:</b> A	Blu-ray	player	would	be	needed	in	a	home	theater	PC	but	is	not	used for	shared	disk	storage<br/> <b>C.  Correct:</b> A	redundant	array	of	inexpensive	disks	(RAID)	array	is	a	good	choice	for a	home	server.	A	RAID-5	can	be	configured	to	store	a	high	volume	of	data,	have better	performance	than	typical	drives,	and	provides	fault	tolerance<br/> <b>D.  Incorrect: </b>A	High-Definition	Multimedia	Interface	(HDMI)	is	used	for	graphics, not	disks","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"67","question":"Which of the following is the definition of an ST fiber connector? <br/><br/>","option1":"Synthetic Tip","option2":"Standard Tip","option3":"Steel Tip","option4":"Straight Tip","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"68","question":"Customer satisfaction is best achieved by <br/><br/>","option1":"never minimizing the customer's problems","option2":"being defensive","option3":"talking to coworkers while interacting with customers","option4":"being judgemental","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"69","question":"SCSI hard drives can spin ata maximum speed of","option1":"5,400 rpm","option2":"7,200 rpm","option3":"10,000 rpm","option4":"15,000 rpm","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"70","question":"Which of the following video connectors can display the                    HIGHEST resolution ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Composite","option2":"HDMI","option3":"VGA","option4":"S-video","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"71","question":"While attempting to resolve an issue, a customer talks to                    the technician about a recent activity that has no                    relevance on the repair. Which of the following is the                    MOST appropriate response? <br/><br/>","option1":"Ask the customer for a timetable about recent activities","option2":"Let the costumer complete their statement and then continue resolving the issue","option3":"Document the customer’s statement and continue resolving the issue","option4":"State that the activity is not relevant to the repair and continue resolving the issue","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"72","question":"Which of the following is MOST likely used at a large company? <br/><br/>","option1":"Windows 7 Home Premium","option2":"Windows 7 Professional","option3":"Windows XP Professional","option4":"Windows 7 Starter","answer":"BC","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"73","question":"Hubs, switches, routers, VoIP phones and NIC cards all have which of the following out of the box? <br/><br/>","option1":"PS/2 port","option2":"IP addresses","option3":"HDMI","option4":"MAC addresses","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"74","question":"Which of the following is a best practice when applying thermal paste?<br/><br/>","option1":"Follow the CPU manufacture’s guidelines and apply the correct amount of thermal paste","option2":"The more thermal paste applied, the better","option3":"Use as much as desired, as long as it is the most popular thermal paste","option4":"The less thermal paste applied, the better","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"75","question":"Which of the following is an example of an APIPA address?<br/><br/>","option1":"10.20.30.40","option2":"169.254.43.40","option3":"172.30.22.159","option4":"192.168.23.110","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"76","question":"A supervisor has asked a technician to configure some                    Windows 7 PCs with some pre-established shared printers.                    The printers are all accessed via a wireless network. Where                    would a technician go in Windows 7 to add these printers?<br/><br/>","option1":"%SystemDir%\Resources","option2":"Enter the paths to the printers in the Registry","option3":"Start >Devices and Printers >Add a printer","option4":"Start >Devices and Printers >Add a Device","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"77","question":"A technician is deploying Windows 7 in a company. The                    supervisor wants to ensure that greatest flexibility is                    provided for the employees when printing. Which of the                    following lists defines all of the supported Windows 7                    interfaces?","option1":"USB, Network, LPT, and Wireless","option2":"USB, IR, Bluetooth, and Network","option3":"IR, LPT, and USB","option4":"IR, LPT, Network, USB, and Wireless","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"78","question":"A custom configured PC with surround sound audio, HDMI                    output, and a compact form factor would be MOST suited to                    which of the following applications?<br/><br/>","option1":"Thick Client","option2":"Gaming PC","option3":"Audio / Video Editing Workstation","option4":"Home Theater PC","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"79","question":"Which of the following network types would be MOST likely used on a high school campus? <br/><br/>","option1":"MAN","option2":"LAN","option3":"PAN","option4":"WAN","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"80","question":"A laptop docking station does which of the following?<br/><br/>","option1":"A laptop docking station does which of the following?Allows the user to synchronize mobile devices without additional hardware","option2":"Allows the user to connect one device to a monitor, network drop, and USB printer","option3":"Allows the user to connect wireless devices more efficiently","option4":"Allows the user to protect sensitive data more effectively","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"81","question":"Which of the following wireless encryption technologies is the WEAKEST?<br/><br/>","option1":"WPA2","option2":"WEP","option3":"WPA","option4":"TKIP","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"82","question":"Which of the following hard drive types has no moving parts?<br/><br/>","option1":"Solid State","option2":"IDE","option3":"SCSI","option4":"SATA","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"83","question":"Which of the following media types supports recording multiple times?<br/><br/>","option1":"DVD-R","option2":"CD-RW","option3":"DVD+R","option4":"DVD-RW","answer":"BD","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"84","question":"Which of the following is a type of internal battery in a laptop computer?<br/><br/>","option1":"UPS","option2":"CMOS","option3":"DC adapter","option4":"Cooling/battery pad combo","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"85","question":"Which of the following is the major architectural distinction between the North Bridge and South Bridge chipsets?<br/><br/>","option1":"The North Bridge connects the main motherboard PCI/AGP controller with the processor","option2":"The South Bridge connects the processor bus with the higher end expansion buses","option3":"The North Bridge connects the processor bus with the lower end ISA expansion bus","option4":"The South Bridge offers higher communication speeds than the North Bridge","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"86","question":"Which of the following BEST describes the ATX 12V feature?<br/><br/>","option1":"An ATX power supply that is designed to version 12 of the ATX standard","option2":"An ATX power supply with an additional 12 volt connector","option3":"An ATX power supply designed for cases smaller than 12 inches","option4":"An ATX power supply that uses a 12-pin V-shaped connector","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"87","question":"The speed in which a microprocessor works is termed<br/><br/>","option1":"buffering speed","option2":"pass-through speed","option3":"bit-time speed","option4":"clock speed","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"88","question":"Which of the following is MOST commonly used as a heat transfer medium within a computer?<br/><br/>","option1":"Power supply","option2":"Case fan","option3":"Thermal compound","option4":"Anti-freeze","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"89","question":"Which of the following memory modules can be installed at a 333MHz bus speed and operate at that speed?<br/><br/>","option1":"PC133","option2":"PC1600","option3":"PC2100","option4":"PC2700","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"90","question":"Which of the following video standards has the LOWEST maximum colors?<br/><br/>","option1":"VGA","option2":"XGA","option3":"SVGA","option4":"SXGA","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"91","question":"Which of the following is a device used to connect multiple computers to a single display device?<br/><br/>","option1":"LED","option2":"Router","option3":"KVM","option4":"CRT","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"92","question":"Which of the following technologies can support the MOST devices simultaneously?<br/><br/>","option1":"USB 1.1/2.0","option2":"SCSI","option3":"FireWire B","option4":"IEEE 1394","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"93","question":"A personal area network (PAN) is MOST often created utilizing which of the following technologies?<br/><br/>","option1":"IEEE 802.3","option2":"HomeRF","option3":"IEEE 802.11g","option4":"Bluetooth","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"94","question":"Which of the following BEST describes how a laser printer works?<br/><br/>","option1":"Toner sticks to photoconductive areas on a drum","option2":"Heat from the printhead melts the ink onto the paper","option3":"Heat from the printhead boils the water-based ink","option4":"Small wires strike and transfer ink from a ribbon","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"95","question":"A technician is troubleshooting an issue and has implemented a solution. Which of the following would be the NEXT step the technician should take?<br/><br/>","option1":"Verify full system functionality","option2":"Test the theory to determine cause","option3":"Document findings, actions, and outcomes","option4":"Ask the user open ended questions about the issue","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"96","question":"The phrase \"Blue Screen\" is often used to refer to which of the following?<br/><br/>","option1":"CMOS checksum error","option2":"An improperly configured video card","option3":"STOP error","option4":"A malfunctioning monitor","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"97","question":"A user reports that their laptop is very hot to touch when it is operating. Which of the following could be the cause of the increased laptop temperature?<br/><br/>","option1":"The heat sink may not be properly seated to the processor","option2":"The path of air flow may be blocked by dirt or other debris","option3":"The laptop LCD screen may be too bright and should be adjusted","option4":"The fan may not be operating properly","answer":"ABD","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"98","question":"An assistant for a company prints out most documents on legal size paper and would like to set legal as the default selection for the default printer. Which of the following statements accurately describes how to make legal the default selection?<br/><br/>","option1":"In the word processing software, go to File>Print>Properties and select the option for Legal under Paper Size","option2":"On the printer, remove all paper that is letter sized and replace with legal","option3":"In the Printer and Faxes applet, right click the default printer> Properties> Advanced Tab> Printing Defaults. Under paper size, select legal and then select apply","option4":"On the printer, make the default setting for Tray 2 Legal","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"99","question":"A customer brings in a laptop and states that it will not power on. The keys are making a much louder sound than normal when pressed. Which of the following is the MOST likely cause?<br/><br/>","option1":"Custom keyboard installed","option2":"Faulty battery","option3":"Bad AC adapter","option4":"Liquid spilled into laptop","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"100","question":"After a power outage, a technician finds that a particular computer no longer powers on. After extensive troubleshooting, the technician determines that the problem is due to a failed power supply. Which of the following is the MOST likely cause of the power supply failure?<br/><br/>","option1":"The computer was not connected to a surge protector","option2":"The power supply had an emergency deactivation switch engaged","option3":"The power supply was not providing power to enough internal devices","option4":"The power supply has overheated","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"101","question":"Which of the following describes the requirements for specialized 64-bit programs?<br/><br/>","option1":"Requires 64-bit processors and 64-bit operating systems","option2":"Requires 64-bit processors but can run on 32-bit operating systems","option3":"Can run on 32-bit processors but requires 64-bit operating systems","option4":"Can run on 32-bit processors and 32-bit operating systems but at a slower speed","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"102","question":"While using Windows 7, the startup continually freezes and prevents the logging in process. Which of the following utilities would be BEST to use when troubleshooting this issue?<br/><br/>","option1":"Safe Mode","option2":"Windows Explorer","option3":"Dxdiag","option4":"Event Viewer","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"103","question":"Which of the following is true in reference to restore points?<br/><br/>","option1":"Once System Restore is used to restore a system the change is irreversible","option2":"System Restore can only be run in normal mode","option3":"The operating system establishes both the date and data to be archived","option4":"System Restore can be done by a user prior to hardware and software changes","answer":"CD","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"104","question":"Which of the following is true regarding WINS?<br/><br/>","option1":"Supports the HOSTS file","option2":"Supports single network environments only","option3":"Performs NetBEUI name resolution","option4":"Performs NetBIOS name resolution","answer":"D","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"105","question":"Which of the following BEST describes the difference between CAT5e and CAT6 UTP?<br/><br/>","option1":"CAT6 can support higher transfer rates","option2":"CAT6 simply revises former CAT5e standards","option3":"CAT5e can support higher transfer rates","option4":"CAT6 adds special shielding for each pair of wires","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"106","question":"Which of the following services is directly impacted by the distance from the user's location to the switching office?<br/><br/>","option1":"Plain Old Telephone Service (POTS)","option2":"Digital Subscriber Line (DSL)","option3":"Integrated Services Digital Network (ISDN)","option4":"Voice over IP (VoIP)","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"107","question":"Which of the following in Windows Firewall will allow user's programs and services access to ports?<br/><br/>","option1":"Exceptions","option2":"Guest accounts","option3":"Phishing","option4":"Automatic Update","answer":"A","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"108","question":"Which of the following is a biometric security feature that allows access to a PC?","option1":"Logical token","option2":"Fingerprint scanner","option3":"RSA token","option4":"Smartcard reader","answer":"B","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"109","question":"Which of the following is the safety procedure to adhere to when a technician has a laptop battery failure?<br/><br/>","option1":"Destroy the battery","option2":"Dispose of battery in an incinerator","option3":"Recycle the battery","option4":"Store battery in storage room","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"110","question":"Which of the following are essential skills for help desk personnel?<br/><br/>","option1":"Active listening skills","option2":"Ability to communicate with varying levels of customer expertise","option3":"Ability to guess and complete the user's sentences","option4":"Ability to infer a solution to a problem with limited facts","answer":"AB","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"111","question":"A user wishes to share files between his Apple Computer and Windows 7 PC. What protocol will he most likely employ?<br/><br/>","option1":"SMB","option2":"TCP","option3":"FTP","option4":"IMAP","answer":"A","explanation":"The Server message Blocks(SMB) protocol permits users to                       share files and printers between systems.                       FTP(File transfer Protocol) allows users to transfer                       files between computers, but usually not used over the                       Internet (rather than within a LAN). IMAP (Internet                       Message Access protocol) provides remote email access.","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"112","question":"David is troubleshooting a completely dead computer with a                    No Power issue. Which of the following should he do first                    to fix this issue? <br/><br/>","option1":"Check if the wall outlet is supplying power","option2":"Test the power supply","option3":"Replace the CMOS battery","option4":"Check if the UPS is working","answer":"A","explanation":"The first step in troubleshooting this problem would be                       to check if the wall outlet supplying the power is                       working correctly. Then, proceed to the other components                       that are related to the power subsystem; including the                       power supply, the UPS, and power connectors. <br/>                      Isolate the points of failure or components that could                       go wrong and cause the issue. Next, establish a logical                       order that should be followed to troubleshoot an issue.                       This order determines the components that should be                       checked first, followed by the rest (from the point of                       origin to the destination). In this case, the power                       originates from the wall outlet. Hence, it should be                       checked first","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"113","question":"A high-end user has a computer with multiple CPUs at the                    office and wants to simulate the processing results on his                    home computer with a single CPU. What technology might you                    recommend to this user <br/><br/>","option1":"Multi-threading","option2":"Multicore","option3":"Hypertransport","option4":"VMWare","answer":"A","explanation":"You would recommend Multi-Threading to this user, which                       allows a single CPU to simulate multi-CPU technology,                       processing two separate sets of instructions.<br/>                      In Multi-Threading, the operating system sees two virtual                       CPUs, even though only one is present. A multicore                       processor physically contains two or more actual                       processor cores in one CPU. Hypertransport is an AMD                       technology unrelated to Multi-Threading, and 64-bit                       refers to a type of CPU architecture, the other type                       being 32-bit","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"114","question":"David purchased a new IDE hard drive and installed it on                    his computer. He switched ON and found that the new hard                    drive was not recognized. Which of the following should he                    check for FIRST?<br/><br/>","option1":"Jumpers on the hard drive","option2":"Cable sequence","option3":"Drivers that need to be loaded","option4":"Hard drive manufacturer Website information","answer":"A","explanation":"If a new hard drive is not recognized, the most crucial                       aspect to be checked for is the jumper setting on the                       hard drive. The jumper setting should be chosen to                       either Cable Select or Slave and Master, based on where                       the drive is connected. <br/>                      The most common jumpers on a hard drive are Cable Select,                       Master, and Slave. If Cable Select is chosen, the                       motherboard will choose whether to make the drive                       primary or secondary. If Master is chosen, the hard                       drive will function only if it connected to the primary                       master or secondary master. If Slave is chosen, the hard                       drive will function only if it connected to the primary                       slave or secondary slave","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"115","question":"Sarah is experiencing a strange problem with her computer.                    The computer shuts down unexpectedly every half hour. Which                    of the following could be the most probable cause of the                    issue?","option1":"Malfunctioning processor cooling fan","option2":"Faulty RAM","option3":"Faulty hard drive","option4":"Dead CMOS battery","answer":"A","explanation":"The most probable cause of a computer shutting down                       unexpectedly is a malfunctioning processor fan. In the                       absence of a component which can dissipate heat                       generated by the processor, the processor overheats.                       Eventually, when a threshold temperature is reached,                       the OS shuts down the computer.<br/>                      The four main causes that contribute to a processor                       shutting down are: <br/>                      1. Hardware issue with the processor fan <br/>                      2. Hardware issue with the heat sink that is used to                       dissipate the heat from the processor <br/>                      3. Dust and dirt accumulated on the processor fan makes                       it less effective<br/>                      4. Not enough thermal glue between the processor and                       heat sink","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"116","question":"David is using a laptop computer with a 2.4 GHz processor.                    However he notices that the processor is operating at                    1.5GHz only. Which of the following could be the possible                    explanation? <br/><br/>","option1":"The processor pins are bent","option2":"The processor is not seated properly","option3":"The processor is being throttled","option4":"The processor is over-clocked","answer":"C","explanation":"If a processor is operating at a speed lower than the                       one it is designed to operate at, the processor is most                       likely being throttled. This is done to reduce the                       dissipated heat and the power consumption in a computer.<br/>                      CPU throttling, also known as dynamic frequency scaling,                       is a technique that runs the processor at a lower                       frequency (or, speed) than it is designed to operate                      This is primarily done for the following reasons:<br/>                      1. To reduce heat dissipation in poorly cooled systems <br/>                      2. To conserve battery in laptop computers. Operating                       laptop processors at lower speeds results in less heat                       generation and reduces cooling costs<br/>","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"117","question":"Jane is trying to connect a flash drive to her friend’s                    desktop computer. The drive doesn’t seem to work in any of                    the USB ports. However, the drive works on her laptop.                    Which of the following could be the most likely cause of                    the issue?<br/><br/>","option1":"The drive works only on laptop computers","option2":"The processor is faulty","option3":"The drive is faulty","option4":"USB is turned off in the desktop BIOS","answer":"D","explanation":"Since the drive is working on the laptop computer, it                       can be inferred that the flash drive works fine. Most of                       the time, a good flash drive does not work on a computer                       because the USB option will be turned OFF in the CMOS                       setup. Another cause for a flash drive to not work could                       be faulty USB ports on the desktop computer. Verify the                       integrity of the ports by connecting good-known USB                       devices to these ports<br/>                      The sequence of steps to follow when a USB drive does not                       work on a USB port is: <br/>                      1. Try using the drive in any other port. If it works on                       any one of the slots, that means the other slots are                       faulty <br/>                      2. Try using another good-known drive on these ports <br/>                      3. Check if the USB option is turned ON in the CMOS                       setup <br/>","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"118","question":"David notices that his computer’s CPU utilization is often                    above 75%. Which of the following could he do to improve                    the speed of the computer and reduce the CPU utilization                    percentage?<br/><br/>","option1":"Increase the RAM","option2":"Upgrade the CPU","option3":"Upgrade the hard drive","option4":"Upgrade the network adapter","answer":"B","explanation":"A very high CPU utilization factor that constantly stays                       above 75% indicates that the CPU resources are being                       over-utilized. The CPU needs to be upgraded <br/>                      A number of bulky applications installed on the computer                       can take up a considerable amount of CPU resources.                       Background processes or a virus could also be a cause of                       the high CPU utilization factor <br/>                      Constantly check for any unknown or unnecessary programs                       or processes running on your computer and disable them                       from your Task manager or the msconfig command","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"119","question":"When a user boots his computer, the monitor goes black. After investigating, you find out that he has set the refresh rate too high. How can you fix this problem?<br/><br/>","option1":"Reboot the computer","option2":"Press F1 while booting","option3":"Boot in VGA mode and change the refresh rate","option4":"Delete the boot.ini file","answer":"C","explanation":"","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"120","question":"Which of the following combination of components can                    deliver the best performance on a computer?<br/><br/>","option1":"PCI for sound card, AGP for the video card","option2":"ISA for the sound card, PCI for the video card","option3":"AGP for the sound card, PCI for the video card","option4":"PCI for both cards","answer":"A","explanation":"Of the combinations given here, a PCI and AGP combination                       delivers the best performance. PCI supports a maximum bus                       speed of 133 MB/s on a shared bandwidth. AGP supports a                       1.066 MB/s speed on a dedicated bandwidth<br/>                      A motherboard with AGP slots and 2-3 PCI slots is                       preferred. AGP cards can be used to obtain optimal video                       performance and PCI cards can be used for other                       additional purposes like TV, audio, and network                       connections","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"121","question":"How many EIDE drives can be connected on a computer at any one point in time?<br/><br/>","option1":"6","option2":"8","option3":"2","option4":"4","answer":"D","explanation":"you can place 4 IDE drives on a computer with 2 IDE                       sockets. Each socket supports 2 IDE devices<br/>                      In general a motherboard (non-SATA) has 2 IDE sockets:                       IDE1 and IDE2. Up to 4 devices can be connected on these                       sockets","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"122","question":"John wants to upgrade his computer with more RAM. Which of the following should he check for to determine the maximum amount of RAM supported by the motherboard?<br/><br/>","option1":"Motherboard documentation","option2":"Notations on the backside of the Motherboard","option3":"Instructions on the RAM","option4":"Right Click My Computer> Select the General tab","answer":"A","explanation":"The best place to check for information on the maximum                       amount of hardware supported on a motherboard is in the                       motherboard documentation<br/>                      A specific motherboard model is designed to support a                       specific amount of hardware resources. Before upgrading                       components like the processor, RAM, or the hard drive,                       check the motherboard documentation for the maximum                       amount of hardware support and the specific variant of                       the hardware supported","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"123","question":"Which of the following is the best method to remove a flash drive that has been inserted into a USB port?<br/><br/>","option1":"Restart the computer and then unplug it","option2":"Unplug the drive after using the Safely Remove Hardware icon in the system tray","option3":"Directly unplug the device from the USB port","option4":"Turn off the laptop and then unplug it","answer":"B","explanation":"Flash drives should be removed from the computer using                       the Safely Remove Hardware icon in the notification area<br/>                      A USB drive has a file system, just like a hard drive                       does. If the power to the machine is cut, or the drive                       is pulled out during a write, this will result in                       incomplete data and possibly a corrupted file system on                       the drive. The \"Safely Remove Hardware\" bit calls for                       all programs accessing the drive to complete whatever                       reads or writes they are performing, as the drive will                       be removed. When all I/O is complete, the OS removes the                       drive from its list of usable drives and then tells you                       it's safe to remove it","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"124","question":"Which of the following computer components retain a significant lethal electrical charge even after the device is unplugged?<br/><br/>","option1":"Monitor","option2":"Processor","option3":"RAM","option4":"Hard drive","answer":"A","explanation":"Monitors operate at high voltages with a high amount of                       electric charge. CRT monitors can store up to 24 KV.                       Hence the back of the monitor should not be opened                       unless you are trained to do so <br/>                      Of the components mentioned here, only monitors store a                       high amount of static electricity. Components like                       processor, RAM and hard drive do not store the amount of                       static electricity that could prove lethal","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"125","question":"Jonathan has added some more components to his computer and                    wants to replace the power supply. Which of the following                    should he check for to replace the power supply effectively?<br/><br/>                   a. Color sequence on the motherboard power supply connector <br/>                   b. Type and number of supply connections<br/>                   c. Support for international power supply voltages above                    241 V <br/>                   d. Total wattage of power supply<br/><br/>","option1":"a,d","option2":"a,c","option3":"a,b","option4":"b,d","answer":"D","explanation":"Three things you need to check for before you replace                       the power supply are: <br/>                      - Type of connectors on the supply<br/>                      - Number of connectors on the power supply<br/>                      - Total wattage of the power supply<br/><br/>                      Power supply provides power to all the components on the                       computer. Before replacing the power supply, check for                       the type, number of supply connectors, and the wattage to                       ensure the proper working of the power sub system","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"126","question":"Sarah is trying to print a document from her workstation. She can see her document displayed in the print queue, however it does not print. The printer is fully functional. Which of the following steps should she take to print the document?<br/><br/>","option1":"Restart the print spooler","option2":"Clear everything in the print queue","option3":"Delete and recreate the printer object","option4":"All of the above in that order","answer":"A","explanation":"To fix this problem, restart the print spooler. To                       restart the spooler service, click Start, right click                       My Computer, and then click Manage. Expand Services and                       Applications, and then click Services. In the details                       pane, right click the Print Spooler service, and then                       click Start <br/>                      Clearing the entries in the print queue, or deleting and                       recreating the print object will not help","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"127","question":"David installed a new set of drivers for one of his hardware components. Since then, the computer has not been able to boot to the OS. What could be the first step in resolving this problem?<br/><br/>","option1":"Rewrite all the lines in the CONFIG.SYS or AUTOEXEC.BAT","option2":"Check if the hardware device is plugged in properly","option3":"Reinstall the operating system","option4":"Reboot to the Last Known Good Configuration","answer":"D","explanation":"Many times, a new set of drivers may not be compatible                       with the operating system. Hence, the computer fails to                       boot to the OS and freezes. Use the Last Known Good                       Configuration from the advanced boot menu to start your                       computer by using the most recent settings that worked<br/>                      The Last Known Good Configuration feature is a recovery                       option that you can use to start your computer by using                       the most recent settings that worked. The Last Known                       Good Configuration feature restores registry information                       and driver settings that were in effect the last time                       the computer started successfully","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"128","question":"While playing a stereo audio CD, you notice that adjusting any attributes with the left hand speaker affects the right hand speaker. What are the most probable causes?<br/><br/>","option1":"The right hand speaker is plugged to the left connector on the sound card","option2":"An IRQ conflict exists","option3":"The volume controls are muted","option4":"You need to run windows utility from the correct working directory","answer":"A","explanation":"The audio connector from the speaker is connected to the                       line-in port that controls the left speaker in the setup.                       Rearrange the settings to connect the connectors to the                       appropriate ports<br/>                      If the speaker connections are plugged into the wrong                       connectors, making changes to any of the attributes will                       not be reflected in the right speaker<br/>                      Most motherboards these days come along with an advanced                       configuration manager. This configuration manager lets                       you re-configure your audio ports to two line-in ports;                       one used for a left speaker, and another for a right                       speaker. Even if the ports are configured properly using                       the configuration manager, it is crucial to check the                       physical connections to these ports ","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"129","question":"David had configured a password to restrict access to the CMOS setup. Which of the following should he do to remove this password and access the CMOS setup?<br/><br/>","option1":"Clear the CMOS by shortening the CMOS jumper","option2":"Boot to a floppy and fdisk the drive","option3":"Go into BIOS setup and delete the password","option4":"Boot down the computer while holding down the <CTRL> key","answer":"A","explanation":"To reset or bypass the CMOS password, clear the CMOS                       jumper on the motherboard. This clears all the CMOS                       settings, including the CMOS password<br/>                      The CMOS password is used to protect any unauthorized                       changes to the machine's basic configuration. If you                       forget the password, you will not be able to enter the                       CMOS setup. To clear this password and enter the setup,                       do the following:<br/>                      1. Locate the CMOS jumper on the motherboard<br/>                      2. Remove this jumper from its default location<br/>                      3. Refer to the manual for the password reset location.                       Ideally pin #1 and #2 are default, and pin #2 and #3 are                       used for a password reset<br/>                      4. Keep the jumper in the reset location for 20-30 seconds                       and then place it in the default location","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"130","question":"If a computer is not protected with a UPS, which of the following problems can occur when power is restored after a power failure?<br/><br/>","option1":"ROM needs to be programmed","option2":"The CMOS RAM has a battery failure","option3":"There is danger from a power surge","option4":"The motherboard switch needs to be reset","answer":"C","explanation":"A power surge is likely when power is restored after a                       sudden power failure. This surge could fry and damage                       the components in the PC <br/>                      Computer components can withstand only a certain degree                       of power fluctuation. Although they have a primitive                       voltage regulator circuit, these are not equipped to                       withstand very high fluctuations. A UPS with voltage                       regulator circuitry is very important to protect the PC                       from power spikes","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"131","question":"Which of the following determines the drive letter while installing a second hard drive on the computer?<br/><br/>","option1":"Amount of memory","option2":"Operating system","option3":"Position on cable","option4":"Drive manufacturer","answer":"C","explanation":"The position of the drive on the cable determines the                       letter assigned to the drive<br/>                      The Windows 7 operating system uses the following logic                       to assign drive letters:<br/>                      1. Assign the drive letter A to the first floppy disk                       drive and B to the second floppy disk drive<br/>                      2. Assign a drive letter, beginning with C to the first                       active primary partition recognized on the first                       physical hard disk<br/>                      3. Assign subsequent drive letters to the first primary                       partition upon each successive physical hard disk drive<br/>                      4. Assign subsequent drive letters to every recognized                       logical partition, beginning with the first hard drive                       and proceeding through successive physical hard disk                       drives<br/>                      5. Assign subsequent drive letters to any RAM Disk<br/>                      6. Assign subsequent drive letters to any additional                       floppy or optical disc drives","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"132","question":"John is planning on upgrading his BIOS. What is the most                    important step to be performed before upgrading the BIOS?<br/><br/>","option1":"Make a note of all the BIOS settings","option2":"Shut off the UPS","option3":"Unplug all connectors","option4":"Save the BIOS upgrade files on to a floppy disc","answer":"A","explanation":"Upgrading a BIOS (also known as flashing) is a crucial                       step. Any settings made to the present version of BIOS                       must be recorded. This is to make sure that the same                       settings can be made to the new version of the BIOS<br/>                      Upgrading a BIOS version is also known as flashing the                       BIOS. The new version of BIOS may have a different                       interface and menu setup. It is crucial to make a note                       of all the settings, so that they can be implemented in                       the new version<br/>                      Take extra precaution during flashing. If computer loses                       power during the flashing process, the motherboard could                       be permanently damaged","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"133","question":"You just made a CD boot disk and want to test it. You put                    the disk in the drive and restart the computer but it boots                    up to the Windows 7 GUI. What could have caused this?","option1":"The BIOS is set to boot the hard drive first","option2":"The disk is set to write protect","option3":"You did not set the boot sector of the disk to active","option4":"None of the above","answer":"A","explanation":"In this case, the PC is looking for the boot sector in                       the hard drive first. To make it search for the boot                       sector in the CD drive, ensure that the CD drive is set                       higher in the boot devices lists<br/>                      BIOS defines a list of boot devices by priority, which                       should be searched for the boot sector when a computer                       boots. Make sure that you assign the drive as a first                       boot device that you want the computer to boot from.                       In this case, set the CD drive as the first boot device","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"134","question":"Mary is a graphic interface designer who intends to use a lot of heavy applications on her computer. She has added two new applications and her work involves keeping at least 4 applications running concurrently. At this point in time, her computer slows down if she opens more than 3 applications concurrently. Which of the following components should she consider upgrading?<br/><br/>","option1":"Motherboard","option2":"Processor","option3":"Hard Drive","option4":"Memory","answer":"D","explanation":"Mary should consider upgrading her memory, or RAM. A lot                       of programs running simultaneously on the computer can                       consume a high amount of RAM. It is important to                       optimize one of the two. Either have enough RAM, or do                       not run a lot of programs simultaneously<br/>                      All the applications running on the computer are                       temporarily transferred to the system memory. In case the                       system memory is insufficient, it uses the hard drive for                       virtual memory. The motherboard and processor play a                       crucial role while installing the applications.                       Although the hard drive plays a crucial part in running                       the programs, it is a memory upgrade that speeds up the                       applications running on the computer<br/>                      Always keep track of the minimum amount of RAM required                       by applications used. Make sure that the sum of minimum                       RAM required by applications does not exceed the RAM on                       your computer","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"135","question":"A customer has purchased a new printer and connected it to                    his Windows 7 Home desktop using a USB cable. The computer                    has detected the printer connected to the USB port.                    However, he complains that the printer is not printing.                    What is the most likely cause of this problem?<br/><br/>","option1":"The USB port is not working","option2":"The printer is not working","option3":"The printer is not compatible with the computer","option4":"The printer driver needs to be loaded","answer":"D","explanation":"Since the printer is being detected, it is not a problem                       with either the USB port or the printer. The only                       possibility is that the appropriate version of the                       printer driver is not loaded<br/>                      The following aspects that need to be checked while                       connecting a printer:<br/>                      1. Check if the printer is USB compatible <br/>                      2. Check if the appropriate version of the driver is                       loaded","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"136","question":"John is experiencing problems with a slow start-up process                    when he switches ON the computer. Which of these utilities                    can be used to stop certain applications from starting                    automatically when the computer boots up?<br/><br/>","option1":"CONFIG","option2":"REGEDIT","option3":"SYSEDIT","option4":"MSCONFIG","answer":"D","explanation":"Msconfig is a utility that can be used to either allow or                       deny programs from starting automatically when the                       computer boots up. Msconfig can be activated by typing                       msconfig in the Run option on the Start Menu<br/>                      When you install a number of applications on the                       computer, the amount of free RAM available decreases                       significantly. Apart from the fact that these                       applications use RAM when they run, most of them start                       automatically when the computer boots up","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"137","question":"David recently updated his network card driver. After this                    update, he is not able to connect to the internet. The                    device manager shows that the driver is not compatible.                    Which of the following could help him to restore the old                    version of the driver?<br/><br/>","option1":"Update Driver","option2":"Modify Driver","option3":"Roll back Driver","option4":"Uninstall Driver","answer":"C","explanation":"Use the Roll Back option available in the Device Manager                       to load the earlier version of the driver that worked                       fine<br/>                      It is common to have driver issues when a new driver is                       loaded. The computer does not specify if the driver is                       compatible when the driver is installed. But once the                       computer is rebooted after the installation, the device                       fails to function. You can go and reset the driver                       version to the one that worked earlier. To do so, go to                       Device Manager, right click the device under                       consideration, click Properties, click the Driver tab                       and then click the Roll Back Driver option ","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"138","question":"John is booting his computer for the first time in 2 weeks.                    After the CMOS set-up screen, the monitor displays an error                     message which states \"NTLDR is missing\". Which of the                    following options should he use to fix this problem?<br/><br/>","option1":"Boot with a second hard drive","option2":"Boot using the Last Known Good Configuration","option3":"Perform a system restore","option4":"Boot using the Recovery Console","answer":"D","explanation":"Use the Recovery console to fix the \"NTLDR is missing                       error\". You can fix missing or damaged boot files using                       the Recovery console<br/>                      The most common causes for a computer to display the                       error \"NTLDR is missing\" are:<br/>                      1. The computer is booting from a non-bootable device<br/>                      2. HDD is not set up in the BIOS<br/>                      3. Corrupt NTLDR and/or NTDETECT.COM file<br/>                      4. Mis-configured boot.ini file","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"139","question":"John wants to enable the Hibernate option on his Windows 7                    laptop computer. Which of the following is the right path                    to enable Hibernation?<br/><br/>","option1":"Right click Desktop, select Properties &gt; Screen Savers &gt; Monitor Power &gt; Power &gt; Hibernate","option2":"Right click Desktop, select Properties &gt; Select Settings &gt; Monitor Power &gt; Power &gt; Hibernate &gt; Enable","option3":"Right click Desktop, select Properties &gt; Select Desktop &gt; Monitor Power &gt; Power &gt; Hibernate &gt; OK","option4":"Right click Desktop, select Properties &gt; Select Desktop &gt; Monitor Power &gt; Power &gt; Power Schemes","answer":"A","explanation":"To enable the Hibernate option, Right click Desktop, select Properties &gt; Screen Savers &gt; Monitor Power &gt; Power &gt; Hibernate <br/>                      The Hibernate option saves your current desktop state to                       your hard disk so that you can resume where you left off,                       then shuts down your computer. Hibernate mode consumes                       less electricity, takes slightly longer to resume, and                       reduces the dependency on a good power source, since                       everything is written to the disk","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"140","question":"John has been using a computer for the past 6 months,                    loading a lot of software and media on the computer. He has                    never connected his computer to the Internet. For the past                    few weeks, his computer has been slow to respond to any                    commands to open a file or copy files. Which of the                    following options could make his computer faster?<br/><br/>","option1":"Disk Defragmenter","option2":"Antivirus software","option3":"Firewall software","option4":"Upgrading the processor","answer":"A","explanation":"Use Disk Defragmenter to increase the access speed by                       rearranging files stored on a disk to occupy contiguous                       storage locations. To use Disk Defragmenter, you can                       select it from Start &gt; Programs &gt; Accessories &gt;                       System Tools or use a software package such as Norton                       Utilities that has a disk optimization program built                       into it<br/>                      Most of the time when a hard drive is full of data, the                       programs are slow to respond. This is because the data                       stored on the hard drive is not stored sequentially.                       Data is divided into smaller chunks and stored at                       different locations on the hard drive. When a program is                       required to open, these chunks of data have to be picked                       up from different parts of the hard drive<br/>                      Disk defragmenter assembles data related to a program or                       software in a sequential manner, thus reducing the access                       time. This in turn makes the computer respond faster","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"141","question":"Jack is experiencing problems accessing the internet on his                    office computer. Although he can ping the xyz.com IP                    address, he cannot ping the domain name xyz.com. Which of                    the following steps could fix his problem?<br/><br/>","option1":"Use the scan disk command","option2":"Check the DNS settings","option3":"Check the Device Manager","option4":"Check the IP address","answer":"B","explanation":"Check the DNS settings on the computer. To do so, right                       click the network connection and click Properties.                       Choose Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) and then click                       Properties. Verify if the correct DNS server IPs have                       been entered<br/>                      If a system can ping the destination using the IP address                       but not the domain name, check the DNS settings on the                       computer. This may be a problem due to issues with DNS                       resolution","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"142","question":"Which of the following commands can be used to create a                    disk image of a hard disk?<br/><br/>","option1":"Sysprep","option2":"Xcopy","option3":"Shadow copy","option4":"Copy disk","answer":"A","explanation":"The sysprep command is used to create a disk image of                       the hard disk. The sysprep command can be activated from                       the command prompt<br/>                      Sysprep is a tool designed for corporate system                       administrators, OEMs, and others who need to deploy the                       Windows 7 operating system on multiple computers","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"143","question":"Which of the following commands are used to clear the                    screen when using the Command Line Interface on Windows 7?<br/><br/>","option1":"CLS","option2":"REM","option3":"CD","option4":"DIR","answer":"A","explanation":"CLS is the command line utility used to clear the                       command prompt window<br/>                      CLS is a command used by the command line interpreters                       to clear the screen or console window of commands and                       any output generated by them. It does not clear the                       user's history of commands ","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"144","question":"Which of the following commands should you use if you want                    to defragment your E drive using the command line interface                    on Windows 7?","option1":"defrag E:","option2":"defragment E","option3":"defrag E/","option4":"defrg E:","answer":"A","explanation":"The syntax used for a defragmentation command is defrag                       volume:. In this case, the command to be used is defrag                       E:<br/>                      A method of performing the defragment operation using                       the GUI is: <br/>                      1. Open My Computer<br/>                      2. Right click the local disk volume that you want to                       defragment and then click Properties<br/>                      3. On the Tools tab, click Defragment Now<br/>                      4. Click Defragment","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"145","question":"John wants to know the different switches that can be used                    with the ping command. Which of the following should be                    typed after the actual command to display a list of                    switches available with that command?<br/<br/>","option1":"/?","option2":"/help","option3":"/*","option4":"/h","answer":"A","explanation":"/? is a common switch that displays a list of switches                       that are used with a command<br/>                      This command can be used to find the different                       functionalities offered by a command. For example typing                       ping /? displays all the switches that can be used with                       the ping command","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"146","question":"Which of the following can be used to control the amount of                    disk space consumed by network users on a network?<br/><br/>","option1":"Disk Quotas","option2":"Disk Cleanup","option3":"Security Center","option4":"Disk Defragmenter","answer":"A","explanation":"Disk quota should be used to control the amount of disk                      space consumed by network users on a network. The function                      of setting a disk quota to disks is to allocate limited                      disk space in a reasonable way<br/>                     A practical implementation of a disk quota is when an                      administrator in an organization sets a limit on drive                      space to ensure that available resources are equitably                      and reasonably distributed among the users of the                      operating systems on a home or business network. It helps                      to prevent the use of more resources by one user, which                      may detriment the usage of another user","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"147","question":"What is the best way to change the drive a Windows computer boots from?<br/><br/>","option1":"Swap in a different hard drive","option2":"Use the BIOS to change the boot order","option3":"Insert a CD with an operating system","option4":"Using the MSCONFIG utility","answer":"B","explanation":"Use the BIOS utility to change the boot order<br/>                      In situations where a boot disk hangs every time, you                       will need to use the BIOS utility to circumvent it<br/>                      BIOS stands for basic/input output system","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"148","question":"You need to delete unused files on a Windows 7 computer in                    order to free up extra hard drive space. Which utility                    should you use?<br/><br/>","option1":"Disk Cleanup","option2":"DEL","option3":"SCANDISK","option4":"Disk Defragmenter","answer":"A","explanation":"Use the Disk Cleanup utility to free up hard drive space                       on your computer. To use Disk Cleanup, click Start &gt; All                       Programs &gt; Administrative Tools &gt; System Tools &gt; Disk                       Cleanup<br/>                      Disk Cleanup is a computer maintenance utility included                       in Microsoft Windows that is designed to free up disk                       space on a computer user's hard drive. The cleanup                       process first involves searching and analyzing the hard                       drive for files that are no longer of any use. It then                       proceeds to remove the unnecessary files, freeing up disk                       space on the hard drive","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"149","question":"You are trying to fix boot issues on a Windows 7 computer                    using the Recovery Console. Which of the following commands                    can you use to write a new Windows boot sector code on a                    boot partition?<br/><br/>","option1":"Fixboot","option2":"Diskpart","option3":"Fixmbr","option4":"Fxboot","answer":"A","explanation":"Use the fixboot command to write new boot sector code.                       It is a Recovery Console command that writes a new                       partition boot sector to the system partition that you                       specify<br/>                      The syntax for this command is fixboot (drive). The                       drive in the command is the drive that a boot sector                       will be written to and will replace the system partition                       that you're currently logged on to. If no drive is                       specified, the boot sector will be written to the                       system partition that you're currently logged on to<br/>                      For example, the command fixboot c: will write the boot                       sector to the partition that's currently labeled as the                       C: drive-most likely the partition you are currently                       logged on to. The command is usually used to deal with a                       corrupted Windows boot sector","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"150","question":"David is getting an error message on his screen which reads \"Non-system disk or disk\" error.                    How would you start troubleshooting this issue?<br/><br/>","option1":"Look for the boot sector in an operating system","option2":"Dump out the virtual memor","option3":"Check if the keyboard is plugged in","option4":"Re-install the operating system","answer":"A","explanation":"The most likely cause of this error message is a missing                       operating system or a failure to locate the boot sector                       in an operating system<br/>                      When the computer fails to locate a boot sector with an                       operating system installed on any of its disks, a                       missing operating system is the most likely cause","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"151","question":"David is switching ON his computer after a month, and an                    error message displays stating \"No operating system                    found\". Which of the following is NOT a possible cause of                    this issue?<br/><br/>","option1":"A device in SYSTEM.INI cannot be found","option2":"No operating system was installed","option3":"There are corrupt boot files","option4":"The boot sector is corrupt","answer":"A","explanation":"If a device cannot be found in SYSTEM.INI, it will not                       lead to the error message \"No operating system found\"                       No operating system found, corrupt boot.ini files, or a                       corrupt boot sector can lead to this error message<br/>                      Many times you may delete a program or application from                       your computer, but one of the files is still called by                       the System.ini, or the Registry. This leads to the error                       message. To fix this:<br/>                      1. Open System.ini in Notepad or with Sysedit<br/>                      2. Search for the file name and delete the entire line<br/>                      3. If it is not found in System.ini, run Regedit, and                       find the filename<br/>                      4. Delete the and close Regedit","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"152","question":"Your Windows 7 computer displays a memory dump error. Which                    of the following would contribute to the physical memory                    dump error?<br/><br/>","option1":"When the computer detects a condition from which it cannot recover","option2":"When a device driver problem occurs","option3":"When a user logs off incorrectly","option4":"When there is a problem with the system RAM","answer":"A","explanation":"The computer displays a memory dump error when it detects                       a condition that it cannot recover from<br/>                      A fatal error in a program automatically triggers a                       memory dump error. When the computer performs a                       \"physical memory dump,\" it takes all the stored parts                       of the working memory and puts them onto your hard drive                       and restarts the computer. The next time Windows loads,                       the files are wiped and all working memory data is lost","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"153","question":"You can create a restore point on your Windows 7 computer.                    How can you do so?<br/><br/>","option1":"Open System Tools and use the System Restore application","option2":"Open C drive and run the System Restore application","option3":"Open Backup in System Tools and run the Restore application","option4":"Open System Restore in the Task Manager","answer":"A","explanation":"To create a restore point, follow these steps<br/>                      1. Click Start &gt; All Programs &gt; Accessories >                       System Tools &gt; System Restore<br/>                      2. Choose Create A Restore point, and click Next..<br/>                      3. Provide a restore point description. Click Create<br/><br/>                      A restore point is a copy of your system configuration                       at a given point in time. Restore points are created in                       three ways: manual, automatic, and restore points                       created before installations. Restore points are useful                       for when Windows fails to boot, but the computer appears                       to be fine otherwise, or if Windows doesn't seem to be                       acting correctly and you think it was because of a                       recent configuration change","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"154","question":"You want to install Automatic updates on your computer at                    3:00 PM every day. Which of the following depicts a path                    that can be used to configure the automatic installation of                    Windows updates at the same time each day?<br/><br/>","option1":"Open Automatic Updates on the Start menu, select the Automatic (Recommended) radio button, and specify the time","option2":"Open Windows Updates on the Start menu, select the Automatic (Recommended) radio button, and specify the time","option3":"Open Automatic Updates in the Administrative Tools menu, select the Automatic (Recommended) radio button, and specify the time","option4":"Open Windows Update Scheduler in System Tools, select the Automatic (Recommended) radio button, and specify the time","answer":"C","explanation":"A standard way of configuring the automatic installation                       of Windows updates at the same time each day is to Open                       Automatic Updates on the Start menu, select the                       Automatic (Recommended) radio button, and specify the                       time<br/>                      The Automatic Updates tab in Windows 7 lets you configure                       how you want to handle updating the OS. You can specify                       that you want to automatically download updates, notify                       the user when updates are available, or turn off the                       feature. You can also specify that you want Windows XP                       to notify you of updates you declined to download at an                       earlier point in time","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"155","question":"John is experiencing a problem with his computer. The                    computer does not boot to the operating system and the                    message \"NTLDR is missing\" appears every time the system                    is turned on. What is the troubleshooting step he should                    perform?<br/><br/>","option1":"Run FIXMBR.EXE","option2":"Reload the operating system","option3":"Run the Recovery Console","option4":"Check for diskette","answer":"C","explanation":"Use the Recovery Console to fix the \"NTLDR is missing                       error\" You can fix missing or damaged boot files using                       the Recovery Console. The Recovery Console is a                       text-based startup of Windows that gets you to a command                       prompt similar to the Windows command prompt. Here you                       can copy or expand the system and booting files<br/>                      The most common causes for a computer to display the                       error \"NTLDR is missing\" are:<br/>                      1. The computer is booting from a non-bootable device<br/>                      2. HDD is not set up in the BIOS<br/>                      3. Corrupt NTLDR and/or NTDETECT.COM file<br/>                      4. Mis-configured boot.ini file","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"156","question":"Martha gets an error message every time her system boots up.                    The error message reads \"A service did not start\" Where                    is the best place to look for more information on this                    error message?<br/><br/>","option1":"System Event Log","option2":"Application Log","option3":"Security Log","option4":"Dr. Watson log","answer":"A","explanation":"All system logs related to services, driver, and startup                       can be viewed in the System Log section of the Event                       viewer. To open Event viewer, choose Start &gt; Programs &gt;                       Administrative Tools &gt; Event Viewer. Choose the System                       link to view the system logs<br/>                      In the Event viewer, System Event log you can find all                       system related logs like services, driver, startup,                       etc. The Application log and Security logs can be used                       to find all information related to the Application                       related events and security related events","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"157","question":"John is working in the Network repair and troubleshooting                    unit with a DSL service provider. He is trying to fix an                    issue with packets being lost enroute to the destination.                    Which of these utilities can be used to find the number of                    hops a packet takes from the source to the destination                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"tracert","option2":"nbtstat","option3":"nslookup","option4":"netstat","answer":"A","explanation":"tracert is the network troubleshooting tool that                       displays the number of hops taken by a packet from the                       source to the destination. The syntax for a tracert                       command is tracert hostname<br/>                      tracert is the most commonly used command for network                       troubleshooting under conditions of intermittency or                       packet loss. The timing information from tracret can be                       useful for detecting a malfunctioning or overloaded                       router","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"158","question":"David has been told by a Technical Support Executive to                    clear all temporary internet files from his computer to                    improve the internet access speed and reliability on his                    computer. Which of the following utilities should he use                    ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Disk Cleanup","option2":"CHKDSK","option3":"Disk Management","option4":"Disk Defragmenter","answer":"A","explanation":"Disk cleanup utility can be used to clear the temporary                       internet files on the computer. To use the disk cleanup                       utility:<br/>                      1. Click Start, and then click Run. Type cleanmgr, and then click OK<br/>                      2. Select the drive-letter for the current Windows installation and then click OK<br/>                      3. Select Temporary Internet Files from the list<br/>                      4. Uncheck all the other entries and click OK<br/>                      5. Click Yes to confirm deletion<br/>                      Internet Explorer copies any images or HTML files from                       websites you visit frequently to a directory on your                       hard drive. Although these cached contents quicken your                       access to pages that have been already accessed, a large                       number of temporary internet files can slow down your                       computer. Clean this folder regularly","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"159","question":"Mark has implemented a Firewall on his corporate network. A                    client reports that he is not able to access the FTP site                    outside the network. Which port is being filtered ? <br/><br/>","option1":"21","option2":"25","option3":"53","option4":"110","answer":"A","explanation":"The FTP uses ports 20 and 21 for its operation. If the                       users of a network need FTP access, ports 20 and 21 must                       be left unfiltered on the firewall<br/>                      File Transfer Protocol (FTP) is a standard network                       protocol used to exchange files over an Internet                       Protocol computer network. FTP servers use TCP port 21                       to listen to incoming connections from clients. Data                       connections use port number 20. Make sure these ports                       are not filtered on the firewall","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"160","question":"George has just attached a computer with an NIC to a                    network. He is not sure if the NIC has a physical                    connectivity with the network. Which of the following                    demonstrates that there is successful physical connectivity                    between your NIC and the network ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Being able to ping the local host successfully","option2":"Glowing NIC LEDs","option3":"Device Manager shows that the NIC is OK","option4":"Able to boot the PC successfully","answer":"B","explanation":"The best way to ensure that a physical connectivity                       between the NIC and the network is valid is to check the                       glowing NIC LEDs. As long as there is a packet exchange                       between the computer and the network, the LEDs glow<br/>                      While troubleshooting a network, it is very crucial to                       check the NIC status before you proceed further. The                       green LINK LED on the NIC confirms the integrity of the                       physical connectivity","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"161","question":"Which of the following network troubleshooting tools helps                    you find the path taken by a data packet from the source to                    the destination ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Winstat","option2":"Ping","option3":"Tracert","option4":"Netstat","answer":"C","explanation":"Tracert is a utility used to determine the route taken                       by packets across an IP network. By showing a list of                       routers traversed, it allows the user to identify the                       path taken to reach a particular destination on the                       network<br/>                      This can help identify routing problems or firewalls                       that may be blocking access to a site. Tracert is also                       used by penetration testers to gather information about                       network infrastructure and IP ranges around a given host.                       It can also be used when downloading data and if there                       are multiple mirrors available for the same piece of                       data, one can trace each mirror to get a good idea of                       which mirror would be the fastest to use","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"162","question":"You want to access a remote host across a network through a                    terminal window. Which of the following protocols would you                    choose to achieve this ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Telnet","option2":"HTTP","option3":"SMTP","option4":"IMAP4","answer":"A","explanation":"Of the protocols mentioned here, Telnet is a network                       protocol used on the Internet or local area networks to                       provide a bidirectional interactive communications                       facility. It provides access to a command-line interface                       on a remote host via a virtual terminal connection,                       which consists of an 8-bit byte oriented data connection                       over TCP<br/>                      You can enter commands through the Telnet program and                       they will be executed as if you were entering them                       directly on the server console. This enables you to                       control the server and communicate with other servers on                       the network. To start a Telnet session, you must log                       into a server by entering a valid username and password.                       Telnet is a common way to remotely control Web servers","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"163","question":"Which of the following protocols are responsible for                    translating a fully-qualified domain name into the IP                    address ? <br/><br/>","option1":"ARP","option2":"DHCP","option3":"WINS","option4":"DNS","answer":"D","explanation":"The Domain Name System or DNS is a protocol that translates                       domain names into IP addresses. It translates domain                       names meaningful to humans into the numerical                       identifiers associated with networking equipment for the                       purpose of locating and addressing these devices                       worldwide<br/>                      DNS is a distributed database system that uses the                       client-server model. The nodes of this database are the                       name servers. Each domain or sub-domain has one or more                       authoritative DNS servers that publish information about                       that domain and the name servers of any domains                       subordinate to it. The top of the hierarchy is served by                       the root name servers","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"164","question":"Which of the following protocols are used to send messages                    to the e-mail server for relaying ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP)","option2":"Post Office Protocol, version 3 (POP3)","option3":"Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP)","option4":"Internet Message Access Protocol, version 4 (IMAP4)","answer":"A","explanation":"SMTP is used to send messages to a mail server for                       relaying. It is a text-based protocol in which a mail                       sender communicates with a mail receiver by issuing                       simple command strings and supplying necessary data over                       a TCP connection<br/>                      SMTP is only a delivery protocol. It cannot pull messages                       from a remote server on demand. Protocols such as POP and                       IMAP are specifically designed for retrieving messages                       and managing mail boxes","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"165","question":"You are a technician and a network user calls up complaining                    that he is not able to access the network resources. What                    is the first thing that you should do ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Check for a link light on the network adapter","option2":"Check the TCP/IP settings on the computer","option3":"Check the network cable","option4":"Check the switch","answer":"A","explanation":"If a user is not able to access network resources, the                       first thing that you should do is to check to be sure                       the link lights on the NIC are working. The link lights                       should blink with a solid or blinking green<br/>                      If the Link LEDs are verified to be working, then you                       can proceed further with the troubleshooting, assuming                       that physical connectivity is intact. If the link lights                       do not work, then troubleshoot for no physical                       connectivity","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"166","question":"As a technician of ABCD.com, if you are asked to configure                    a PC that needs to be connected to the Internet, what are                    the 2 things you will check for FIRST ? <br/><br/>","option1":"NetBIOS address of the DHCP server and the default gateway","option2":"IP address of the DHCP server and the default gateway","option3":"IP Address of the e-mail server and DHCP server","option4":"Host name of the computer and the IP address of the default gateway","answer":"D","explanation":"While configuring the IP address on a computer, the first                       thing to check for is the IP address of the default                       gateway and the DNS server. Email-server, DHCP server,                       and hostnames are not crucial while configuring the IP                       address<br/>                      The default gateway is an ISP-provided device that                       connects the user to the Internet. It can be a DSL or                       cable modem. Along with the default gateway details,                       the user also needs to enter valid DNS server IPs,                       preferably two","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"167","question":"What is the default subnet mask for an IP address                    192.168.10.10 ?<br/><br/>","option1":"255.255.255.0","option2":"255.0.0.0","option3":"255.255.0.0","option4":"255.255.255.255","answer":"A","explanation":"The default subnet mask for the IP address                       192.168.10.10 is 255.255.255.0<br/>                      The method to find out the subnet mask for a given IP                       address is:<br/>                      1. Check the class of the IP address given<br/>                      2. If asked for a default subnet mask for a particular                       class of IP, the subnet mask would have as many 255s as                       the sequence of alphabets. For example, class A will                       have one 255, class B will have two 255s and class C will                       have three 255s","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"168","question":"You ping the loopback address, but do not receive any                    response. What do you think is the most likely cause                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"DSL router is down","option2":"DNS server is offline","option3":"Network card is being throttled","option4":"TCP/IP protocol is not functioning","answer":"D","explanation":"If pinging a loop back address does not give a reply, it                       is most likely that the NIC is faulty and the TCP/IP                       protocol is not functioning<br/>                      127.0.0.1 is the loopback address of a computer. Pinging                       the loopback address determines if the NIC is working.                       In case the ping request fails, then the NIC needs to be                       re-seated or changed","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"169","question":"You are the technician at ABCD.com. You want to ping the                    loopback address on a PC that has been configured with the                    static IP address of 192.168.1.122. What commands would you                    use to achieve this ? <br/><br/>","option1":"PING 0.0.0.0","option2":"PING 127.0.0.1","option3":"PING 192.168.1.122","option4":"PING 255.255.255.255","answer":"B","explanation":"Use the ping 127.0.0.1 command to perform the loopback                       test. This test should be performed locally on the                       computer<br/>                      The loopback address sends outgoing signals back to the                       same computer for testing. In a TCP/IP network the                       loopback IP address is always 127.0.0.1 and pinging it                       will return a reply. The loopback address allows a                       network administrator to treat the local machine as if                       it were a remote machine","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"170","question":"Which of the following commands can be used to flush the                    old copy of IP information and get a new copy of IP                    information ? <br/><br/>","option1":"IPCONFIG /RENEW","option2":"IPCONFIG /RELEASE","option3":"IPCONFIG /ALL","option4":"IPCONFIG /FLUSH","answer":"A","explanation":"Use the ipconfig/renew command to flush the old copy of                       IP information. To access this command, click                       Start &gt; Run &gt; type CMD> type ipconfig/renew<br/>                      This command is used as an intermediate step in flushing                       out troublesome IP information from a network adapter","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"171","question":"Nick bought a new Ethernet NIC and installed it on his new                    PC. He observes that the link lights on the NIC are                    flashing Orange. Which of the following could most likely                    cause this ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Collisions on the network","option2":"Data is being transmitted to the computer","option3":"The network cable is faulty","option4":"The network is down","answer":"A","explanation":"Orange blinking lights on an NIC indicates collisions on                       the network. Successful data transfer will display a                       solid green light. If the network is down or the cable                       is faulty, the light will not glow at all<br/>                      Whenever an NIC LED shows an orange light, it is time to                       consider segmenting the network","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"172","question":"When troubleshooting an error in Mike's network, you                    observe that the IP address of his PC changed after the PC                    was restarted. What is your inference from this ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Computer has a DHCP-based IP address","option2":"DNS server is offline","option3":"DHCP server is offline","option4":"Ethernet cable is a faulty","answer":"A","explanation":"If the IP address changes after a reboot, then it is                        most likely that the computer is using DHCP<br/>                       Generally (though not always), if a computer uses DHCP,                        the computer obtains a different IP address soon after                        the computer boots up. If the IP address changes when                        the PC is booted, then the computer is configured with                        a DHCP-based address","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"173","question":"A PC has been configured with a static IP address of                    192.168.1.122. Bill tries to run the ping 127.0.0.1                    command on this PC, but does not receive any reply for this                    command. What should he infer from this ?<br/><br/>","option1":"The network interface card (NIC) is faulty","option2":"The network cable is faulty","option3":"The technician should run the ping 192.168.1.122 command","option4":"The DNS server is offline","answer":"A","explanation":"If a loopback test fails, it means that the NIC is                       faulty<br/>                      Pinging 127.0.0.1 is known as the loopback test. A                       loopback address tells the computer not to test its                       connections to another computer, but to test its own                       basic network setup. If this test fails, then it can be                       inferred that the NIC is faulty and the card needs to be                       replaced","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"174","question":"The UpwardPro.com network uses an IP proxy that provides                    Network Address Translation. Ted implements IPSec for all                    the internet bound traffic, but observes that he is still                    not able to access the Internet. What has led to this                    issue?<br/><br/>","option1":"Network Address Translation (NAT) does not work with IPSec","option2":"The IP proxy is blocking egress and ingress traffic on port 80","option3":"The IP proxy is blocking egress and ingress traffic on port 1293","option4":"The IP proxy is blocking egress and ingress traffic on port 8080","answer":"A","explanation":"NAT does not work with IPSec since the packet gets                       discarded by the receiving end of the VPN connection<br/>                      A conventional NAT does not work on IPSec packets                       because when the packet goes through a NAT device, the                       source address in the packet changes, thereby                       invalidating the packet. When this happens, the                       receiving end of the VPN connection discards the packet                       and the VPN connection negotiations fail","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"175","question":"You observe that at different divisions of the                    UpwardPro.com office, CAT5e cables are lying around on the                    floor. What should you do about these cables ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Remove the cabling and install a wireless access point","option2":"Reroute the cables using a protective sheath","option3":"Tape the cables securely to the floor","option4":"Inform the administrator about this potential security risk","answer":"B","explanation":"All the CAT5e cables lying on the ground should be                       re-routed using a protective sheath<br/>                      Network cables should never be allowed to be on the                       floor. This may damage the cable and in turn slow down                       or bring down the network. All cables should be                       rerouted using a protective sheath","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"176","question":"As a network administrator of UpwardPro.com, which of                    following is the most important preventive measure that you                    should take up on a regular basis to secure and protect the                    PC?<br/><br/>","option1":"Disable the use of cookies","option2":"Disable all unused features of the web browser","option3":"Run a virus scan of the hard disk drives","option4":"Enable the Windows Firewall","answer":"C","explanation":"To protect your PC, periodically run anti-virus scans on                       your computer. It is important to have a good anti-virus                       that has virus signatures periodically updated<br/>                      Although other tasks like disabling cookies and disabling                       unused features in a browser are useful tasks that                       should be performed, they are of lower priority than                       running a virus scan","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"177","question":"What are the advantages of dial-up over DSL?<br/><br/>","option1":"DSL has a fairly short limit of 18,000 feet from the central office","option2":"Dial-up is faster than DSL","option3":"Dial-up uses a second phone line for internet","option4":"None - Dial-up has no advantages over DSL","answer":"A","explanation":"DSL restricts the connections to 18,000 feet from the                       central office. However dial-up has no such restrictions                       and the user needs only a phone line<br/>                      Apart from distance limitation, DSL is very advantageous                       when compared to a dial-up connection. It is faster and                       more stable","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"178","question":"Which of the following is NOT a feature of the TCP                    protocol ? <br/><br/>","option1":"Provides hardware address to IP address resolution","option2":"Assures reliable delivery","option3":"It is connection oriented","option4":"Uses sockets and ports to exchange data between applications","answer":"A","explanation":"TCP does not provide hardware address to IP address                       resolution. ARP does so<br/>                      TCP is connection oriented and assures reliable delivery                       of packets. TCP uses sockets and ports to exchange data                       between applications. Ports provide a specific and                       universal location for message delivery, while sockets                       use the host IP address, port number, and the type of                       service (TCP or UDP) to create a reliable connection","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"179","question":"Which of the following describes the difference between a                    network hub and a network switch ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Hubs repeat all traffic; switches analyze and intelligently direct the traffic","option2":"Hubs intelligently direct traffic; switches repeat all traffic","option3":"switch has an uplink port to add another switch for expansion. This is absent in a hub","option4":"A hub has an uplink port to add another hub for expansion. This is absent in a switch","answer":"A","explanation":"Hubs repeat all traffic. Switches analyze and                       intelligently direct the traffic<br/>                      Hubs repeat everything they receive and can be used to                       extend the network. However, this can result in a lot of                       unnecessary traffic being sent to all devices on the                       network. Hubs pass on traffic to the network regardless                       of the intended destination<br/>                      The PCs to which the packets are sent use the address                       information in each packet to work out which packets are                       meant for them. Switches control the flow of network                       traffic based on the address information in each packet.                       A switch learns which devices are connected to its ports                       by monitoring the packets it receives and then forwards                       on packets to the appropriate port only. This allows                       simultaneous communication across the switch,                       improving bandwidth","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"180","question":"Jack reports that when the phone rings in his house, the                    wireless on laptops becomes disconnected. Which of the                    following could be the most likely cause ?<br/><br/>","option1":"The cordless phones are 2.4Ghz which interferes with wireless","option2":"The cordless phones are plugged into same outlet as the router","option3":"The cordless phones are 5.8Ghz which interferes with wireless","option4":"The cordless phones are plugged into the RJ11 jack","answer":"A","explanation":"It is most likely for wireless networks to function                       intermittently with a cordless phone operating at 2.4                       GHz in the proximity of the network<br/>                      Three things to be done to avoid interference are:<br/>                      -Move the phone beyond 50 feet of the wireless network<br/>                      -Switch to a 5.8 GHz phone<br/>                      -Use a different channel on the 2.4 GHz phone that does                       not overlap with the WiFi network<br/>","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"181","question":"You are upgrading your company’s infrastructure by                    implementing a video conferencing setup and have begun to                    experience network degradation. You have determined that a                    hub is causing the bottleneck. Which of these network                    devices should you replace your hub with ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Switch","option2":"Amplifier","option3":"Repeater","option4":"Router","answer":"A","explanation":"Replace the hub with a switch. If a hub is causing                       network degradation, a switch is the best option to                       avoid bottlenecks and network degradation<br/>                      The hosts connected to the hub share the total available                       bandwidth, whereas the switch provides a dedicated                       bandwidth when two hosts communicate. Therefore, a                       switch serves as better network connection equipment                       than a hub","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"182","question":"A user is concerned with the security of his laptop’s BIOS.                    The user would not like anyone to be able to access control                    functions except themselves. Which of the following could                    make the BIOS more secure ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Password","option2":"Flash the BIOS","option3":"Encrypt the hard drive","option4":"Create an ACL","answer":"A","explanation":"Setting a BIOS password will nullify the chances of any                       unauthorized individual changing the BIOS settings. To                       set the password, enter the CMOS setup during boot up<br/>                      The BIOS password restricts access to the BIOS setup.                       However, make a note of this password since losing this                       password would require you to make changes to the                       computer hardware","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"183","question":"A technician deploys a computer in a public library and                    wants to create user accounts with limited permissions.                    Which of the following accounts would the technician                    setup?<br/><br/>","option1":"Limited user accounts","option2":"Back up user account","option3":"Power user account","option4":"Administrator user account","answer":"A","explanation":"Limited user accounts restrict a user to Web browsers,                       e-mail programs, productivity programs such as Microsoft                       Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, and                       entertainment programs<br/>                      You can use limited user accounts to assign limited                       privileges to users. All other user accounts mentioned                       here provide user with greater privileges","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"184","question":"A technician is conducting a forensics analysis on a                    computer system. Which step should be taken first                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Get a binary copy of the system","option2":"Search for Trojans","option3":"Look for hidden files","option4":"Analyze temporary files","answer":"A","explanation":"The first step in the forensic analysis of an infected                       system is to obtain the binary copy of the system<br/>                      A system cannot be analyzed or searched for evidence                       using a simple file copy. The investigators need to                       obtain the binary copy to preserve evidence. This copy                       must be tamper-proof and must be capable of independent                       verification","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"185","question":"A newly hired security specialist is asked to evaluate a                    company's network security. The security specialist                    discovers that users have installed personal software, the                    network OS has default settings, no patches have been                    installed, and passwords are not required to be changed                    regularly. Which of the following would be the first step                    to take ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Enforce the security policy","option2":"Install software patches","option3":"Disable non-essential services","option4":"Password management","answer":"A","explanation":"The first and the foremost task to be performed is to                       enforce a good security policy which covers all the                       security measures<br/>                      Of all the measures mentioned here, a good security                       policy can ensure that software patches are installed                       and disable all non-essential services","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"186","question":"Which of the following is the major difference between a                    worm and a Trojan horse ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Worms are self replicating while Trojan horses are not","option2":"Worms spread via e-mail while Trojan horses are not","option3":"Worms are a form of malicious code while Trojan horses are not","option4":"There is no difference","answer":"A","explanation":"Worms self replicate in the system, while Trojans                       performs undisclosed malicious activities on the host                       computer<br/>                      A computer worm is a self-replicating computer program.                       It uses a network to send copies of itself to other                       nodes and it may do so without any user intervention.                       Unlike a virus, it does not need to attach itself to an                       existing program. Worms almost always cause at least                       some harm to the network, if only by consuming bandwidth.                       Viruses almost always corrupt or devour files on a                       targeted computer. A Trojan is a malware that appears to                       perform a desirable function but in fact facilitates                       unauthorized access to the user's computer system","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"187","question":"John wants to transfer some information to his computer                    from his friend’s USB drive. Which of the following should                    he do before transferring information ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Scan the USB drive for viruses and other malicious codes","option2":"Nothing needs to be done. Transfer information","option3":"Ask his friend to scan the USB drive in his computer","option4":"Insert the USB drive on the computer and check if it works","answer":"A","explanation":"Although John can ask his friend to scan the USB drive,                       it is likely that his friend may not have a good                       anti-virus or an updated one<br/>                      The USB drive should be scanned well before using it","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"188","question":"Which of the following is a method of removing or bypassing                    a BIOS password ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Remove the CMOS battery","option2":"Change memory card","option3":"Re-connect all drive cables to the motherboard","option4":"Restart the computer","answer":"A","explanation":"To remove a BIOS password, just reseat the CMOS battery.                       A computer stores its settings and keeps the time even                       when it is turned off and unplugged because these parts                       are powered by a small battery inside the computer                       called a CMOS battery<br/>                      Before removing the CMOS battery, make sure your computer                       is off and that you're properly grounding yourself. Grab                       the edge of the battery and pull it up and out of its                       holding container. Make sure you write down all the BIOS                       settings before you pull out the battery","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"189","question":"John is concerned about users using thumb drives to connect                    to USB ports on company workstations, contemplating a data                    theft of sensitive files. What should he do to fix this                    concern ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Disable USB in the workstation BIOS","option2":"Seal all USB ports","option3":"Install Antivirus","option4":"Install Firewall","answer":"A","explanation":"The best way to disable access to USB ports on a                       computer is to disable the USB in the CMOS setup and                       assign a CMOS password. This way the users will either                       not be able to use USB devices or go to the CMOS setup                       and make changes<br/>                      This method is used by most organizations to protect the                       integrity of corporate data","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"190","question":"Which of the following best describes the purpose of a SSID                    in a wireless network ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Identifying the network","option2":"Better signal strength","option3":"Better connectivity","option4":"Encryption","answer":"A","explanation":"SSID broadcast beacons are released at periodic intervals                       out into the open. These beacons have wireless network                       information. A user can logon or use the network using                       this SSID beacon<br/>                      Although this is a feature of a wireless network, it can                       be a disadvantage. Any passerby can get hold of this                       beacon and access the wireless network. Two things to be                       taken care of are:<br/>                      1. Protect the network with a password<br/>                      2. Set the beacon interval as high as possible to                       minimize the chances of unauthorized access","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"191","question":"Which of the following should be done to secure a wireless                    network?<br/><br/>                   a. Use a secure SSID.<br/>                   b. Use MAC ID filtering.<br/>                   c. Switch off the wireless router.<br/>                   d. Use only Windows XP operating systems<br/><br/>","option1":"a,b","option2":"b,c","option3":"a,c,d","option4":"a,d","answer":"A","explanation":"Generic SSIDs can be easily hacked. Two ways of                       protecting wireless network access is by using secure                       SSIDs and by restricting the computers accessing the                       wireless network by filtering the MAC IDs<br/>                      Wireless network security is crucial. Although the above                       mentioned methods are not absolutely fool-proof, they                       provide a considerable level of security on your                       wireless network","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"192","question":"David is experiencing problems with unauthorized access of                    his wireless network. He has already changed his SSID and                    enabled MAC ID filtering. Which of the following can                    significantly reduce the chances of his wireless network                    bring accessed ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Install sniffers around the wireless network","option2":"Keep the access point in a metallic shield","option3":"Increase the time interval between SSID beacons","option4":"Decrease the time interval between SSID beacons","answer":"C","explanation":"Increasing the intervals between SSID beacons ensures                       that fewer beacons are sent out in a given time                       interval<br/>                      SSID beacons are sent out in the open by access point at                       periodic intervals. By increasing the time interval                       between the beacons, fewer beacons are sent out in a                       given time interval, providing better security. This                       setting can be enabled through the access point's                       control panel","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"193","question":"Which of the following can significantly increase the risk                    of unauthorized access on a wireless network? <br/>                   a. Using WEP authentication.<br/>                   b. Using low time intervals between successive beacons.<br/>                   c. Using generic SSIDs.<br/><br/>","option1":"a,b","option2":"a,c","option3":"b,c","option4":"a,b,c","answer":"D","explanation":"Using WEP authentication, low time intervals between                       beacon frames, and generic SSIDs can significantly                       increase the risk of your wireless network being                       detected and hacked<br/>                      WEP is an older method of authentication; the latest is                       WPA2. Always change your access point password from the                       one provided by the manufacturer. Use a secure SSID                       access key","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"194","question":"Which of the following authentication modes are most                    secure ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Biometric","option2":"Password","option3":"Access card","option4":"Photo-identity","answer":"A","explanation":"Biometrics is the most secure access method since it                       uses human characteristics to grant or deny access.                       Human attributes cannot be imitated easily<br/>                      Biometrics is the science and technology of measuring                       and analyzing biological data. In information                       technology, biometrics refers to technologies that                       measure and analyze human body characteristics, such as                       fingerprints, eye retinas and irises, voice patterns,                       facial patterns, and hand measurements for                       authentication purposes","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"195","question":"Which of the following programs are not destructive, but                    leach bandwidth in networks and can turn a speedy machine                    into a slow one ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Malware","option2":"Adware","option3":"Spyware","option4":"Grayware","answer":"D","explanation":"Grayware refers to applications or files that are not                       classified as viruses or Trojan horse programs, but can                       still negatively affect the performance of the computers                       on your network and introduce significant security risks                       to your organization<br/>                      Grayware often performs a variety of undesired actions                       such as irritating users with pop-up windows, tracking                       user habits, and unnecessarily exposing computer                       vulnerabilities to attack. Although not considered as a                       serious threat, it should not be allowed to remain on                       the system","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"196","question":"What is the generic term that defines a hacker going through                    your refuse to find critical information ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Dumpster diving","option2":"Refuse searching","option3":"Refuse diving","option4":"Dumpster searching","answer":"A","explanation":"Dumpster diving is the practice of sifting through                       commercial or residential trash to find items that have                       been discarded by their owners, but which may be useful                       to the dumpster diver<br/>                      Always shred any crucial hard copy data before disposing                       it in the dust bins","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"197","question":"Which of these tools should be use to enable auditing on a                    local level ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Local Security Settings","option2":"AD policy","option3":"Group Policy","option4":"User Settings","answer":"A","explanation":"At a local level, the security settings should be                       modified. These include password policy, account lockout                       policy, audit policy, and user rights management.                       To perform this procedure, you must be a member of the                       Administrators group on the local computer, or you must                       have been delegated the appropriate authority<br/>                      It is very crucial to modify these settings to enable a                       high level of security","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"198","question":"Choose the most effective method to prevent computer                    viruses from spreading throughout the network<br/><br/>","option1":"You should enable scanning of all e-mail attachments","option2":"You should require root/administrator access to run programs and applications","option3":"You should prevent the execution of .vbs files","option4":"You should install a host based IDS (Intrusion Detection System)","answer":"A","explanation":"Always scan all e-mail attachments before opening to                       avoid any virus infection on the computer. Other methods                       are mostly an indirect way of avoiding virus infection on                       the computer<br/>                      Use an antivirus that can scan all e-mails coming into                       the network","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"199","question":"Which of the following needs to be done in order to ensure                    that your computer is protected ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Keep updating your antivirus periodically","option2":"Always open all e-mail attachments","option3":"Install a virus to ensure your computer is protected","option4":"Never turn on your computer during peak web traffic hours","answer":"A","explanation":"Keep updating your antivirus signatures periodically.                       This way the antivirus will track and filter all viruses                       coming into the computer<br/>                      Keeping the antivirus up to date with the latest virus                       signatures keeps the operating system secure","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"200","question":"What is the best physical way to protect a user's system                    from malicious software attacks ?<br/><br/>","option1":"Delete or restrict all permissions for non-administrators","option2":"Purge all unused registry files regularly","option3":"Delete or restrict power users only from the registry","option4":"Use registry cleaner software programs monthly","answer":"A","explanation":"Never assign high privileges to non-administrators.                       Assign it to individuals who are concerned with the                       security of the setup and know about virus infections                       and risks<br/>                      Installing malicious software can infect the system                       seriously. It is mandatory to grant rights to install                       software to individuals with knowledge of virus                       infections. These individuals would typically install                       software after ensuring the legitimacy of the software.                       Hence the only way to prevent a malicious software                       installation is by restricting permissions for                       non-administrators to install software","isexamquestion":"1"},{"num":"201","question":"Jill is trying to install an antivirus on her computer. In                    spite of repeated attempts she is not able to install the                    antivirus software. What could be the most likely problem                    ?<br/><br/>","option1":"It is an old version of the antivirus software","option2":"She has just re-installed the operating system","option3":"She has Microsoft office running on the computer","option4":"She is logged in as a guest","answer":"D","explanation":"Since she is logged in as a guest, she will not have                       privileges to install any application on the computer.                       She would either need to login as an administrator or                       assign administrator privileges to her account<br/>                      There are many reasons why an antivirus fails to get                       installed. They include:<br/>                      1. Incompatibility with the OS<br/>                      2. Another antivirus on the system<br/>                      3. User who is trying to install is logged in as a guest","isexamquestion":"1"}];